<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rdf:RDF
	xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
>
<channel rdf:about="default">
	<title>VHS</title>
	<link>default</link>
	<description>VHS - default</description>

	<items>
		<rdf:Seq>
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=82" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?on_critical_mass_and_critical_manners" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=69" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://textsfornothing.com/blog/?p=377" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://textsfornothing.com/blog/?p=371" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=34" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=24" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/07/new-project-bad-free-to-download-software-analysis/" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?luke_s_open_web_vancouver_2009_write_up" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=17" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?net_parliament" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?my_open_source_calendar" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?thank_you_for_the_tests" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?lightning_renegade" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://mikecantelon.com/138 at http://mikecantelon.com" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?2009_victoria_jugglefest_high_low_goal_crush_bane_surprise" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?coming_up_in_2009" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://mikecantelon.com/137 at http://mikecantelon.com" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?2009_02_retreat_wrap_up" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?happy_new_year_2009" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=98" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=88" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=3" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=8" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=46" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=52" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=54" />
			<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=58" />
		</rdf:Seq>
	</items>
</channel>

<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=82">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Playing backup CDs on older consoles</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/08/playing-backup-cds-on-older-consoles/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/ssaturn.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ed: I wrote this last year and never finished this. I managed to complete the write-ups for Sega's first two disc-based consoles, but I got caught up in other things before finishing it. Enjoy what I've writen!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the unfortuante aspects of optical media is the fact that the media does happen to deteriorate over time. With that, they become virtually unplayable and thus become just useless pieces of aluminium and plastic. However, as computing power and abilities have advanced, this problem has been sort of solved with the usage of CD burners. It's fairly easy to backup the CD image to a large hard drive and burn them to a recordable disc for later usage. This prevents potential wear and tear of your existing originals and also prevents damage to the console in certain situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page will provide some information on how to deal with certain consoles and their protection mechanisms. Some of the older consoles have no protections at all while others have some rather nasty systems in place.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-82&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sega CD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far, the Sega CD is possibly the easiest console to work with. Just burn your ISO to a CD-R and play away. In some cases, if you feet like it, you can replace the music of your favourite games with alternatives. I did run across some syncing issues with Sonic CD when it came to gameplay and music, but other than that, there isn't much to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sega Saturn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the previous CD-based console, the Sega Saturn happens to be to this very day one of the most difficult consoles to play copied discs on. It stems from the simple fact that the Saturn has a dedicated processor that determines the legitimacy of the disc based on a track on the outer side. No CD recorder can replicate this due to the nature of how this track is placed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, there are two methods to go about using copied discs on the Saturn. However, both require some modification to the console's internals and may prevent wearing issues later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Swap method&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires having one game at all times available to you--in my case, I keep a copy of Virtua Fighter seeing that it came with every Saturn practically. If you own a model 1 Saturn (one with non-round buttons for power and reset), the swap trick is apparently quite easy. However, model 2 Saturns (round buttons) require a bit more work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A guide is available on how to do this, but be forewarned that doing the swap trick can lead to damage to your console if done too many times or too recklessly. The bearings that lock your disc into place may be worn out with repeated swapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Modification&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is a lot more difficult than the swap method simply because it involves some knowledge of working with tightly-built electronics. What is involved is what is known as a &quot;mod chip&quot; being installed inside of your Saturn. The chip simply fools the Saturn into believing that whatever disc is in the console is an original copy. Installation of said chip varies per chip designer and to make matters worse, chips are no longer in active production, so you'll either have to rely on someone having stock, finding it used from a defunct console, or somebody selling a Saturn with a chip pre-installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do a Google search for merchants selling said chips. They seem to run anywhere between $40 CAD ($35 USD) and up in price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the future I'll write up a bit on the Dreamcast (fairly easy) and a few other consoles such as the 3DO.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-08-28T04:34:59+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?on_critical_mass_and_critical_manners">
	<title>lukec: On Critical Mass and Critical Manners</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?on_critical_mass_and_critical_manners</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: activism, blog post, critical manners, critical mass, cycling, mass&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Summary: (comment)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Everytime I think about Critical Manners I get a weird unidentifiable feeling. The idea leaves me feeling a little squirmish, but it wasn't clear to me why. While cycling home from downtown last night I started to get some personal clarity that I'd like to share. I am not going to dwell or defend Critical Mass in this post, I am going to focus on the interplay between Mass and Manners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;versus&quot;&gt;Versus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The similarity in name of the two events tricks your brain into comparing these two different events. I think for a lot of people within the cycling community that have had positive experiences with Critical Mass, Critical Manners is a bit of a face-slap. This gets people's backs up, and we start comparing CMass with CManners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think comparing these two events is a trap; we should be evaluating these events separately, on their own merits. We should do this not only because then we could think openly about how to improve each event and see what the benefits are, but also because these events each have their own spirit. When we evaluate Critical Manners in terms of the goals of Critical Mass, we are sure to be disappointed. And vice-versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what_critical_manners_is_not&quot;&gt;What Critical Manners is not&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Critical Manners is not a protest, it is not activist, it is not making waves, it is not confrontational, it is not pushing the limits. But that is OK, it doesn't need to be. It is not attempting to replace Critical Mass - it is attempting to be an alternative (and complimentary) choice. But with a name so close, I think people with experience with Critical Mass see Critical Manners as something weak, something watered down. This is because they are evaluating the event according to Critical Mass' goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;on_its_own&quot;&gt;On its own&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One insight I had while cycling home last night is that Critical Manners is focused on the present reality. Riders will not be pushing the limits and trying to change laws - instead they will be riding within the current skillset and infrastructure available. The Manners ride should bring positive attention to many issues that Critical Mass does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
By having newbie and experienced cyclists ride together observing the rules of the road, it should be a learning experience; new cyclists will see how veterans handle the common interactions. Where should they ride in the lane? How and when should they change lanes or move with the auto traffic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The Manners ride as currently planned stays on bike lanes and the best areas that cyclists have to ride in. Against Critical Mass criteria, there is little utility in this. But on it's own, this has the possibility to inform a lot of riders about these lanes, about when they're great and when they are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;brainstorming&quot;&gt;Brainstorming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once I dropped the Mass mindframe, I could start seeing more possibilities in what Critical Manners could accomplish. Here are some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Each Manners ride could have a skill theme to focus on. Perhaps an example is &amp;quot;left turns&amp;quot;. Many riders are intimidated to turn like cars do (as cyclists are instructed to do in the Motor Vehicle Act). In a Manners ride, cyclists could see and experience how to do these things safely, in a place with support from other cyclists. Future Manners rides could consider other skills or common situations that riders experience. In this way, the Manners ride could be a place to improve and learn. Imagine if the Media were to catch on and support this! Perhaps this focus on a particular skill would bubble up to the Old Media's attention, and they could help inform drivers about how cyclists are supposed to &amp;quot;turn left&amp;quot; (say). In this way, Manners could be a way to teach cyclists and drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Manners rides could also focus instead on skills on certain types of problems faced by cyclists today. In the first Manners ride, almost the entire route is on really safe bike lanes. Perhaps future rides would consider a route that went on common routes not supported by bike lanes. Again, this could help build confidence of new cyclists in riding on those lanes, supported by other cyclists. It could also raise awareness in the city about where more infrastructure is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
These ideas obviously have some drawbacks and concerns to be addressed. Perhaps skills learning is better done in small groups; large groups of cyclists turning left may block traffic (which would logically then be not &amp;quot;polite&amp;quot;?), or it may be unsafe with our current infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;scalability_and_safety&quot;&gt;Scalability and Safety&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One of the first questions I found myself asking when I learned about Critical Manners is how safe it would be. I think this is an interesting and mis-understood question, so I will dip into it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There seems to be a lack of understanding about why Critical Mass rides as a single blob, corking lanes and not stopping for red lights. For the moment, let's put aside the concerns about interrupting other traffic, and let's consider the issue of rider and driver safety. If there was to be no corking, or ineffective corking, or if riders were to stop at stoplights the cyclists would become interspersed with drivers. The necessary slower pace of cyclists (especially when the group is composed of all-levels riders) frustrates the drivers. The drivers and cyclists both become more erratic, and the theory (and practice from years and years of critical mass rides) shows that there are going to be a lot more accidents or incidents between drivers and cyclists. So by corking, the mass riders are staying together to reduce the overall likelihood of accidents for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think of this as exactly the same as what would happen for a parade. You simply cannot have cars squeezing across a parade, even when the parade momentarily thins out. If you allow cars to drive in dense areas of pedestrians or cyclists, there is simply not the reaction time and too much going on for it to be safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I want to stress that this safety concern isn't just some theory, it seems to be learned from lots of events in the past. The support from the Police shows me that they also understand this concern and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When my friend Jen announced Critical Manners, my first question was about scalability: Does 1 rider ride differently from 10 or 100 or 1000? It appears evident to me that when you have some large number (a &lt;em&gt;critical mass&lt;/em&gt;?) of people/pedestrians/cyclists that the de-facto rules change. Navigating 3000 cyclists from point A to point B as a single mass is much safer than as a single file line that will have much more (net) mingling with cars. This single mass does come at the expense of a temporary delay of other traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So my concern here for the Manners ride is one of safety. If the turnout is very large, it seems to me that there is more risk to individual riders than in the Critical Mass. I think we should be mindful of this, but not let it impact the Manners ride too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;judging&quot;&gt;Judging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So I'm arguing here that it's ultimately not very useful to compare these rides. They have different goals, and different methods of implementation. Having such similar names of the rides may ultimately increase the conflict between these rides and the riders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But I'm also suggesting that we should not judge the Manners ride immediately. We should give it some space and time to learn about it, to see how it goes and to appreciate it's place in the overall ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think it is fantastic that the Manners planners have taken this positive step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When I think about Mass and Manners, I laugh and wish that we could get the public as catalyzed and passionate about issues that &amp;quot;really matter&amp;quot;, like occupying foreign countries or the unprecedented transfer of wealth in our bailouts or the impending global environmental catastrophies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Some awesome comments, and a really well-thought-out piece, which I definitely appreciate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think a lot of people have gotten hung-up on framing the Manners ride inside the goals of the Mass ride, which has certainly led to some confusion (and in rare cases, outrage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm awfully glad that there has been such a huge response to the Mass in its current state, the introduction of Manners, and the fact that cyclists recognize a need for change (though I don't think anyone has a clear idea yet of what exactly that change should look like). Manners is a part of that response, hence the name. I think it's appropriate, at least this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And like you, I agree that Manners in its current incarnation should be short-lived. I would love to see it morph into a more consistent awareness of cycling safely and lawfully (lessons are a great idea) and advocating for better road-sharing by everyone. Cars will not go away, so let's all work on the most positive way to reduce their use that is attractive and productive for &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think Mass has gotten to a place where the protests are less &amp;quot;pro-bike&amp;quot; and more &amp;quot;anti-car,&amp;quot; which doesn't really serve anyone very well. Perhaps this summer is its tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My standard response to the question of more Manners rides has been one of &amp;quot;wait and see.&amp;quot; One of the core purposes of Manners is to promote unity and cooperation, so really I'd like to see cyclists re-uniting in a positive way under any umbrella, whether it's a re-vamped Mass where productive members actively discourage the disruptive behaviours of those only out for anarchy and mayhem, or Manners, or any of the other local cycling groups (pedal etiquette, VACC, BEST, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-Jen Watkiss (Critical Manners)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Guest User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: guest@socialtext.net} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 2:29pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=14 21:29:22 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While not my main point of writing this piece, I do want to state that I am entirely personally supportive of the current format and practice of Critical Mass.  There are people in every crowd that are in it for themselves and not always acting so ... enlightened.  I accept that and try to work with the other 95% of critical massers to have a great ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/57860/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Luke Closs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: luke.closs@socialtext.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 2:48pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=14 21:48:06 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I agree that comparing Critical Manners to Critical Mass is counterproductive to promoting and encouraging cycling as an alternative to driving. Their tactics are not comparable because they &lt;strong&gt;are not the same thing&lt;/strong&gt; as Luke points out. One is a protest. One is a bike ride. Both serve the cause of cycling, of reducing air and noise pollution, of increasing physical health, of saving money and oil, of creating community and physical connection to city streets and neighbourhoods. That said, I see nothing wrong in an anti-car sentiment. Automobiles, while certainly useful and needed in some cases, are killers. Literally. They are unsustainable, both in the wars they fuel and in the pollution they cause. If more people were connected to the very negative outcomes of overdriving, they would not drive, or would not drive as much. This is an important connection to strive to make. Is it confrontational? Yes. But much progressive social change comes with uncomfortable, sometimes dangerous, often illegal confrontation. Think Rosa Parks sitting at the front of the bus. Think students getting shot at Kent State. Think Mohamed Ali refusing to go to war. There are many many examples in recent history of confrontations like these changing the world, for the better. Critical Mass is a spontaneous, self-directed expression of democracy - people coming together to say and show want they want in their society. It's one of the few examples we've got these days. Which is why I'll keep riding! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Guest User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: guest@socialtext.net} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 4:13pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=14 23:13:56 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I wrote a post &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.raulpacheco.org/2009/07/critical-mass-disruptive-mobilizations-and-environmental-awareness/&quot;&gt;criticizing Critical Mass&lt;/a&gt; a short while ago where a lot of controversy arose (I criticized the disruptive nature of the ride). I like your balanced position, too (and well, Jen is also a friend of mine so I'm kind of biased there too - although my friends Karen F and Karen P do ride in Critical Mass). Good post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Guest User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: guest@socialtext.net} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 4:43pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=14 23:43:02 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Great post, Luke. One thing I would ask, and this is a Critical Mass criticism that Critical Manners is addressing, is &amp;quot;How would the impact of Critical Mass be lessened if the route was made public?&amp;quot; You rightly mention parade safety, but parades inform the police of routes and allow traffic to go around them. I think a lot of Critical Mass criticisms would be removed if this one issue was addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/61287/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Chris Simmons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: simmons.chris@gmail.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 5:19pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=15 00:19:54 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I am also hesitant about possible safety issues re Critical Manners if too many cyclists attend. However, it's a great evening to support our fellow cyclists so I plan to drop by David Lam Park at 5:45 and decide at that time if I want to join the ride, cycle around Stanley Park, or just find blackberry bushes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wally Commuter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Guest User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: guest@socialtext.net} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 5:24pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=15 00:24:00 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sorry, I meant to sign my comment, third from the top, right after Luke's. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kate Milberry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And here's my post on Critical Mass occupying the Lion's gate bridge in June: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://misscommunikate.ca/?p=32&quot;&gt;http://misscommunikate.ca/?p=32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Guest User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: guest@socialtext.net} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 8:16pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=15 03:16:32 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
@ Chris Simmons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I tend to agree with your theory that many of the CMass criticisms would be removed if people were simply aware of the route ahead of time.  While I'm sure a number of people would still be stuck sitting in their cars, others who prepared better would be able to alter their transportation arrangements to better work around the mass of bicycles.  My personal concern is getting stuck on a bus in the middle of the Lion's Gate Bridge or somewhere on the Stanley Park causeway.  If at least I knew if/when CMass was going to be hitting the bridge, I could either leave work earlier or later to avoid the congestion.  Likewise, some drivers might choose alternate routes or timetables to reduce any problems that they might have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Best of luck to Jen and Critical Manners, I hope that today's ride went well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-Andrew M&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Guest User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: guest@socialtext.net} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 8:21pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=15 03:21:50 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To both Chris and Andrew - I think what you are forgetting is that no part of Critical Mass is planned, aside from the meeting place and time, because there are no organizers.  It's not that route isn't made public, nobody knows the route ahead of time - the crowd makes the decisions based on who is at the front at any given intersection and where they want to go.  Maybe the route could be influenced, but even so, the crowd will go where it wants.  There are no representatives, everyone has equal control.  The crowd dynamics are actually quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/69007/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;jroger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: jroger@gmail.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 14 11:40pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=15 06:40:26 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yes, the route simply cannot be announced as there &lt;em&gt;is no route&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Someone (you?) could make and announce a route.  But you'd need that critical mass of people to follow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/57860/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Luke Closs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: luke.closs@socialtext.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 15 6:33pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=16 01:33:23 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Good one Luke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I clicked here from another blog where someone wrote that you were wrong to write that Critical Manners is not a protest. Manners is protesting the Mass Ride. I'm glad I read this, your post. I hope it becomes, or at least the method you apply to thinking about the two events becomes a sort of touchstone in this local debate within the cycling community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I love the Critical Mass Ride, and I mean that in the sense that my heart explodes in the mass. For me the ride is an intense emotional experience. (And yes, I've seen some riders behave rudely, but that is such a small part of the experience. Most, (...and this is where I applaud your method, I could write &amp;quot;All&amp;quot; the riders are intensely happy, in the Critical Mass Ride, which would be polarizing, and of course untrue, which doesn't seem to be a concern of those who paint all CM Riders as rude, selfish, uncivilized beasts.) yes, most of the riders are intensely happy and riding in a spirit of celebration and community. This is why I ride in the Mass, an while I'll continue to ride with you all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That said, while reading your post, I began to understand Critical Manners as a positive expression of a part of the cycling community, this part was inspired by the Mass Rides. (Because the Mass Rides are inspiring. You don't read much about the car drivers stuck in traffic who turn of there engines, turn up their radios and dance and cheer in the street, but I've seen it, those beautiful scenes are totally worth it. (and by &amp;quot;it&amp;quot; I mean the shitty reactions the mass ride inspires.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Definitely the beauty (the good) of the Critical Mass Ride inspired Critical Manners, and the same sort of madness that floods supermarkets with products like no fat ice cream and sugar-free, caffeine-free cola, is behind the desire for a community gathering of pure goodness. If I'm in town for the ride I'll do it, but I won't go with my 7 year old son, like I do for the Mass ride, because a stopping and starting mass of riders is going to be a chaotic mess. (that I can't wait to be a part of.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Also, and this needs to be clarified in the local discussion, the ride like all masses isn't homogeneous. I ride in the stream, the happy, smiling, cheering, celebratory stream that is made possible by the corkers, who place themselves in confrontational spaces so the mass can ride freely. The free riders often thank the corkers for what they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Guest User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: guest@socialtext.net} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 18 12:17pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=18 19:17:37 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
tl:dr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/81992/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;alicia nijdam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: alicia.nijdam@gmail.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 18 8:44pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=19 03:44:14 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
@Alicia - I think you mean to use a semi-colon, not a colon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
See &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=tl%3Bdr&quot;&gt;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=tl%3Bdr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/57860/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Luke Closs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: luke.closs@socialtext.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Aug 18 10:45pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=08-=19 05:45:34 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-08-19T05:45:34+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=69">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Best Bluetooth Antenna Ever!</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/08/best-bluetooth-antenna-ever/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/bt/01.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt; I needed a really cheap bluetooth adapter that I could afford to destory or lose. Seeing that going to Best Buy or any other big box store for one of these is just pointless, so I bought it through an online store based out of Hong Kong. I have ordered a tonne of items from them before, so I didn't care too much about what I was going to get. It was likely to be modified so I went with the larger one instead of the tiny one that basically ate a USB port full-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I have a bad habit of cracking open the items I receive from them--warranty status with these guys? Yeah right! However, I didn't expect this when I bought it...&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-69&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/bt/02.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt; After cracking it open, I was presented with four parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parts you see here are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bottom part of case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top part of case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Circuit board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Piece of plastic resembling an antenna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the last item? That's right. The damn antenna was just a piece of plastic not even touching the circuit board at all!&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/bt/04.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Doesn't appear to be a wire going from the plastic piece to the circuit board!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/bt/05.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Aesthetics do not necessarily imply better signal strength!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't updated much in the past while so I figured I'd post this along. Also, forgive me on the crummy photos as I shot them with my camera phone while at work last week.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-08-17T04:17:20+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://textsfornothing.com/blog/?p=377">
	<title>texts for nothing: Misunderstanding Critical Mass</title>
	<link>http://textsfornothing.com/blog/2009/08/06/misunderstanding-critical-mass/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been an interesting month for Vancouver&amp;#8217;s version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Critical_Mass&quot;&gt;Critical Mass&lt;/a&gt;, the leaderless bike ride that takes place on the last Friday of every month in cities around the world. Vancouver&amp;#8217;s July 31 ride became the focus of media hysteria when Mayor Gregor Robertson let it be known that he was &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vancouversun.com/travel/Mayor+seeks+meeting+with+Critical+Mass+organizers+reduce+tension/1845989/story.html&quot;&gt;pissed off&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; about the lack of a predetermined route. Robertson and police chief Jim Chu went so far as to call for a meeting with the &amp;#8220;organizers&amp;#8221; of Critical Mass. Which is kind of ridiculous, since Critical Mass doesn&amp;#8217;t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; organizers &amp;#8212; and Gregor, who has participated in the ride in the past, ought to know that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the ride went ahead as scheduled, and with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vancouversun.com/Colour+creativity+calm+Critical+Mass/1852852/story.html&quot;&gt;minimum of fuss&lt;/a&gt;. (I participated, mainly because I was annoyed by the negative media attention.) But the powers that be haven&amp;#8217;t given up trying to assert control over future rides. Now city councillor Andrea Reimer is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.straight.com/article-245945/critical-mass-bike-ride-should-be-responsive-circumstance-reimer&quot;&gt;complaining&lt;/a&gt; that the ride &amp;#8220;hasnâ€™t been well marshaled, it has been loose. As a result it has made it less easier to cycle and less clear why we are doing it&amp;#8230;. It was good to see more marshals out [at the July ride] and for them to be very clear about why they are riding, right?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look, I know this is hard for politicians to understand, but Critical Mass doesn&amp;#8217;t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; leaders. There are no organizers for the mayor and the police chief to talk to. There are no marshals responsible for maintaining order on the ride. And there is no single goal or agenda or point that Critical Mass is trying to make (beyond a very broad &amp;#8220;Bikes are awesome!&amp;#8221;). Some people participate because they hate cars, others participate to draw attention to how unfriendly Vancouver is towards cyclists, and still others participate simply because it&amp;#8217;s fun. To talk about &amp;#8220;being very clear about why they are riding&amp;#8221; is to completely misunderstand Critical Mass. Even calling it a &amp;#8220;protest&amp;#8221; is a bit of a stretch. Critical Mass is literally just a bunch of people meeting up at the same time and place every month and going for a bike ride together. There is no basis of unity beyond that &amp;#8212; and it&amp;#8217;s definitely not something you need to have leaders to do, any more than my friends and I need a leader when we ride our bikes to a party (or whatever).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Andrea Reimer refers to &amp;#8220;marshals,&amp;#8221; she is probably referring to the self-appointed leaders at the July ride &amp;#8212; the ones who brought their own PA system to address the crowd before the ride began, and then tried to cooperate with the cops to divert the ride according to their own pre-determined plan, without the consent of the other 3,000 participants on the ride. Well, I&amp;#8217;m sorry, Andrea, but those people have no more authority than anyone else. In fact, to the extent that people ignored the self-appointed leaders and did what they collectively wanted to do, I&amp;#8217;d say the ride was a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#8217;s as it should be. Critical Mass &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;#8217;t&lt;/em&gt; have leaders or organizers &amp;#8212; that just creates a target for cops to harass and for politicians to co-opt. Vancouver has been fairly lucky that the authorities are so tolerant of the ride. There are many stories of rides in other cities where the cops cracked down and arrested participants (last year in New York, for example, a cop was caught on video &lt;a href=&quot;http://gothamist.com/2008/07/28/cop_caught_on_video_assaulting_cycl.php&quot;&gt;assaulting a cyclist&lt;/a&gt; during Critical Mass). The recent hysteria may be a sign that the local tolerance is waning. Under the circumstances, it would be a big mistake to give the authorities a target to crack down on. A crowd of 3,000 cyclists is pretty much unstoppable short of overt use of force by the cops; a small group of leaders, self-appointed or otherwise, would be much easier to manipulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why is Vancouver&amp;#8217;s tolerance only waning now, years after the rides began in Vancouver? I think Mike Cantelon has a point when he &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.straight.com/article-245085/critical-mass-hysteria&quot;&gt;connects the current controversy to the Olympics&lt;/a&gt;. After all, the February 2010 ride will be happening right in the middle of the 2010 Winter Games. Mike puts it best in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.straight.com/article-245945/critical-mass-bike-ride-should-be-responsive-circumstance-reimer#comment-11060&quot;&gt;a comment on another story&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;ll only be okay with Critical Mass during the Olympics if they can control it. To move towards this, local politicians want to to see Critical Mass become hierarchal, with leaders they can influence so they have control over the route. They want this ASAP so they can test this control over the half year leading up to the Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think the Olympics are the whole story here, but the powers that be are obviously keen to &amp;#8220;maintain order&amp;#8221; during the Games (hence the &lt;a href=&quot;http://thetyee.ca/Blogs/TheHook/Olympics2010/2009/02/19/SecureBill/&quot;&gt;$900 million security budget&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/canada/british-columbia/story/2009/07/23/bc-vancouver-olympics-bylaw.html&quot;&gt;crackdown on civil liberties&lt;/a&gt;, etc.). There&amp;#8217;s no question that they would love it if Critical Mass had a hierarchy to exert pressure on, so as to avoid any &lt;em&gt;unpleasantness&lt;/em&gt; on February 26, 2010 and every ride thereafter. What worries me is those self-appointed leaders. It&amp;#8217;s not too hard to imagine people like that setting themselves up as Critical Mass &amp;#8220;representatives&amp;#8221; (with the best of intentions, of course) and, ultimately, collaborating with the powers that be. It&amp;#8217;s a classic problem: some event or movement challenges the status quo, the keepers of the status quo push back against it, someone eventually emerges as the voice of compromise &amp;#8212; and sure enough, that event or movement becomes compromised, softening and undermining the &amp;#8220;challenge&amp;#8221; that it poses until it no longer challenges anything at all. Critical Mass is hardly a social movement, but it definitely constitutes a challenge to the status quo, and it does so in a beautifully empowering and non-hierarchical way. It would be a shame to see that radical edge sanded away, yet again, in the name of accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-08-06T21:32:27+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://textsfornothing.com/blog/?p=371">
	<title>texts for nothing: Stop BC library cuts!</title>
	<link>http://textsfornothing.com/blog/2009/07/26/stop-bc-library-cuts/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Here in British Columbia, public libraries get a big chunk of their funding from the provincial government in the form of annual operating grants.&lt;a href=&quot;http://textsfornothing.com/blog/feed/#fn-libfunding&quot;&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; This year&amp;#8217;s grants have yet to be distributed, even though we&amp;#8217;re already four months into the new fiscal year. If that money isn&amp;#8217;t received, we could see &lt;a href=&quot;http://stopbclibrarycuts.ca/public.htm&quot;&gt;substantial cuts to programs and services&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; stuff like access to online resources, sharing of materials between libraries (giving patrons access to stuff that they just can&amp;#8217;t get at their local library), and literacy programs for kids like the BC Summer Reading Club and Books for Babies. The chief librarian at Vancouver Public Library is already talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publiceyeonline.com/archives/004085.html&quot;&gt;reduced hours of operation and even branch closures&lt;/a&gt;. And the head of the BC Library Trustees Association &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timescolonist.com/news/Libraries+talk+funding+with/1823937/story.html&quot;&gt;has pointed out&lt;/a&gt; that &amp;#8220;a cut to this year&amp;#8217;s grant would guarantee there will be cuts in the future.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last election, Premier Gordon Campbell talked about making BC &amp;#8220;the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nupge.ca/node/2436&quot;&gt;best educated, most literate jurisdiction&lt;/a&gt; on the continent.&amp;#8221; Now his government is planning to cut funding for public libraries, which play a fundamental role in education and literacy. Even worse, this is happening at a time when libraries across the province have seen big surges in use because of the ongoing economic crisis. People are using library resources (books, the reference desk, free public Internet access) to look for work, to find other ways to make ends meet, or even just to cope with uncertainty and stress. Not only is the provincial government threatening to undermine an essential service, they&amp;#8217;re doing it at precisely the moment when that service is needed most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heckuva job, Gordo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;fn-libfunding&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;* Clarification from a reliable source: Provincial grants provide about 10 percent of public library funding in BC, on average (although the proportion can be much larger for smaller libraries &amp;#8212; as much as 25 to 50 percent). Most of the funding comes, of course, from the local municipality. To my mind, even 10 percent qualifies as &amp;#8220;a big chunk&amp;#8221; of the budget.
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-07-27T07:35:30+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=34">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Soft-modding your Wii for Homebrew</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/07/soft-modding-your-wii-for-homebrew/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/homebrew_ch.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt; When I buy a device, I expect to be able to do whatever the hell I want to do it. It's my hardware, right? So why must I go through loops and bounds to get the software I want to run on said device to work? And why must the company that makes the software for it make it near-impossible to get anything I want to work on it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the problem everybody who has the same mindset faces with Nintendo's Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a simple guide to getting the Wii to run software that you, the owner could wish to run.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-34&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What you will need&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Wii&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An SD card (1 GB or larger is suggested if you want to do anything useful)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that you don't need much to hack your Wii these days? With the SD card, you might have to try several SD cards until you find one that doesn't act very slow. In my case, I am using an OCZ 1 GB SD card and it seems to be doing the trick. If you're unsure and are willing to spend some cash, just get the Sandisk Wii-branded SD card and that should do the trick. I had to try about three different cards until I found one that worked just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;From here&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a copy of Bannerbomb (&lt;a href=&quot;http://bannerbomb.qoid.us/&quot;&gt;from here&lt;/a&gt;) and follow the directions on the site. They're fairly straight-forward provided that you don't have any issues with your SD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is that you do everything but mess around with the IOS. Boot2 should be more than sufficient to play with and is reversible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things to note&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable WiiConnect24 as you don't want to be caught with a non-working Homebrew Channel thanks to Nintendo's overzealous system updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I haven't had any issues playing online games such as Mario Kart Wii online, so I don't expect the same for any other game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a new update is made available, be sure to follow homebrew websites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiibrew.org&quot;&gt;WiiBrew&lt;/a&gt;, which will offer advice or information. Some updates have passed that haven't messed up the Homebrew Channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your non-Nintendo-licensed channels on a seperate SD card. If you do not, you'll run into problems where your Wii will just lock up trying to load up the SD card channels. SD cards are cheap anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Experiences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bad SD card will result in some odd problems. I managed to get some of my apps to load just fine, but they ended up complaining that they couldn't read the SD card. If you run into a situation where it cannot load the appropriate driver to read the SD card or cannot write to it, besides checking the read/write tab on the card, you might want to just copy the contents of the SD card to another one. This is a problem that resulted in me changing my SD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DVDx in combination with Mplayer will allow one to play DVDs on your Wii, but from my experience, I haven't had any success with getting any disc to play--the movies will just play for a few seconds and then stall or go back to the Mplayer menu (I suspect that it is just playing the buffer). Mind you, a console is not really intended to play movies in the first place and I would suggest otherwise anyway. It does however play the videos I have stored on my USB key without any problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many applications support the use of SMB/CIFS as a method of accessing files stored on a computer. This is great except for one problem: the applications that support it don't allow for backslashes so if you have a domain specified on your file server, you're out of luck. I will be filing a bug report about this or at least suggest to them that they allow the use of domains in SMB file access. For the vast majority of those reading this blog entry, it won't be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things I have done&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't done too much except installed &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/snes9x-gx&quot;&gt;Snes9xGX&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiibrew.org/wiki/QuakeGX&quot;&gt;QuakeGX&lt;/a&gt; on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QuakeGX has been pretty neat to try out. If you use the nunchuck in combination with the Wiimote, you can use the Wiimote to shoot and the nunchuck to move around. It is a bit sensitive, but after a few adjustments, it felt almost natural and a lot of fun. I still prefer the keyboard and mouse, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Snes9xGX, I will admit that I prefer playing everything on both my SNES and Super Famicom (I own both). However, it is the fan-translated games that I have been desiring to play. There are quite a few including Bahamut Lagoon, Seiken Densetsu 3, and Wonder Project J.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/seikendensetsu01.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/seikendensetsu02.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encourage that everybody buys these games before going about acquiring copies elsewhere, but this is one useful function of the Wii. You can also get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.retrousb.com/product_info.php?cPath=22&amp;products_id=31&quot;&gt;adapters&lt;/a&gt; to plug in your SNES controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiibrew.org&quot;&gt;WiiBrew&lt;/a&gt; - A good site for anything and everything relating to Wii homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-07-12T23:41:16+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=24">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Analysis: SUPERAntiSpyware</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/07/analysis-superantispyware/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest problems facing computer users is the plethora of supposed anti-spyware software out there. At random, I decided to pick out SUPERAntiSpyware after doing a simple Google search for &quot;anti-spyware&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/superantispyware/main.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-24&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Background on the software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the EULA and the website, the software is developed by a company that has offices in Oregon. Some searching around on Google indicated that the software company behind it has been active in keeping an eye for any mention of its program. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wilderssecurity.com/showthread.php?t=124523&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on a security forum netted this bit from an employee named Nick Skrepetos who is quoted as saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello all, Nick Skrepetos here from SUPERAntiSpyware.com. If any of you have any questions regarding the product, technology, etc. I am more than happy to answer them, or questions regarding new spyware, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize people think &quot;oh great, another scanner&quot; - but as you will see (actually I hope you won't be infected with the new nasties we are finding) that we can detect and remove many infections that others can't touch as of yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are seeing enormous growth in the rootkit/kernel driver and user mode hooking spyware applications. These applications are the ones that filter the file system and registry so that items can't be &quot;seen&quot; or removed easily. Standard anti-spyware applications won't be able to touch these, as they won't see them. [...]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that an employee of the company has come out on a security forum to discuss his product and answer questions makes this software less scary than it seems because when I downloaded it I came across this in its installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/superantispyware/superantispyware02.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the developer: this can come off as suspicious as it would make me nervous if I came across this on a user's computer and promptly rip it out. Having a consistent name and URL would make me less edgy about the software. It is for this reason that I can comfortably recommend software like Spybot Search and Destroy as well as AdAware--the inconsistency will make me nervous and believe that it is malware. Fortunately, after browsing the site that the publisher refers to, it gives some more &lt;a href=&quot;http://superadblocker.com/about.html&quot;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt; about Nick and his team, which can in some ways put more of a face behind the developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After running the installer, I was happy to find that during the process it doesn't connect to any outside servers if you've told it not to auto-update or send scan results. This puts a bit more confidence in me, but I will have to admit that I found something strange in how it reports processes if you do happen to choose to send the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;VERIFY=yes&amp;#038;
REPORTTYPE=SASDIAGNOSTICITEM&amp;#038;
FILENAME=VMWARESERVICE.EXE&amp;#038;
PROCESSPATH=C:%5cPROGRAM%20FILES%5cVMWARE%5cVMWARE%20TOOLS%5cVMWARESERVICE.EXE&amp;#038;
COMMANDLINE=&amp;#038;
MD5=B1311AEA4C6FDBF1C4E907611E3D47C3&amp;#038;
R&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This line is sent once for every process to their webservers. Why you'd want to send it line-by-line is a bit odd and in some ways bandwidth-consuming. If I were the developer, I'd look into cutting down on this and do it in a different fashion than what is going on here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/superantispyware/superantispyware08.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I ran its full scan, it only found one item on the whole machine, which was in fact a cookie I had picked up while searching for the software in the first place. The fact that it doesn't come up with false positives has made me quite happy and safe in not removing the software. I am not here to review the program as a spyware scanner, so I cannot suggest it as I haven't had the chance to actually test it out and don't intend to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Long term&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left the software running in the VM overnight and left Wireshark to determine if there had been any connections made by the software. The verdict? Nothing appeared on the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I cannot say if it is better than its competition, it is indeed a spyware scanner that doesn't give false positives and doesn't call home when you tell it not to. You should feel safe while installing this.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-07-06T23:50:41+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/07/new-project-bad-free-to-download-software-analysis/">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: New Project: Bad â€œfree to downloadâ€ software analysis</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/07/new-project-bad-free-to-download-software-analysis/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/winxp_vm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a new purpose for this blog: documenting what these &quot;free to download&quot; programs do to your computer. I will run packet analysis to see what data they're sending back home and see if they do what they reportedly intend to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All will be done in a VMWare session so not to polute a production computer in my posession. Hopefully I will stick with this and go on further.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-07-06T00:10:45+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?luke_s_open_web_vancouver_2009_write_up">
	<title>lukec: Luke's Open Web Vancouver 2009 Write-up</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?luke_s_open_web_vancouver_2009_write_up</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: Blog Post, conference, open web&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had a really excellent and energizing time at the Open Web conference. Here are my highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pirate_keynote&quot;&gt;Pirate Keynote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rick Falkvinge of the Swedish Pirate Party gave the opening keynote. The pirates are celebrating their first win of a seat in the EU Parliament. What I found most interesting was how instead of framing the Pirate issues as a &amp;quot;copyright fight&amp;quot;, he explained it as a civil rights issue. &amp;quot;Next generation civil rights&amp;quot;. Should we follow the entertainment industry towards stronger copyright and IP, we must say goodbye to many civil rights and privacy issues that have been part of our society for ages. The Post Secret goes away, whistle blower protection goes away, and others. Not to mention that this quickly becomes un-enforceable as technology continues to march on. And this is all just to save some industry that has refused to adapt to the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rick also compared the current entertainment industry to the Catholic Church back a few hundred years ago. The printing press used to be a government granted monopoly. And then some guy had the crazy idea to make Libraries, and that caused a huge stir - &amp;quot;... but libraries would mean the unwashed masses could read and learn about our culture WITHOUT PAYING!! zomg!&amp;quot;. History has many parallels today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Later on I gave Rick a high five and thanked him for his work. Like a real pirate he said that we are all peers and thanked me. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;women_keynote&quot;&gt;Women Keynote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Angie Byron of the Drupal project gave a talk on Women in Open Source. Her research showed (shockingly!) that women only account for ~1.5% of open source contributions. Her talk focused on how men and women can help change that. Good Stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tor&quot;&gt;Tor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had hear about Tor for a while, through the Vancouver HackerSpaces club, but never completely understood it. Jacob Applebaum (@ioerror) gave a great security talk on Tor. Tor is a secure anonymous proxy for internet communications. He presented how this technology is useful for different kinds of people: regular citizens, companies, law enforcement, whistleblowers, and activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The most interesting part was that all the Tor sites were blocked from our new $800 million dollar convention centre. :( Bell runs the internet service there and has a sneakier proxy than the Great Firewall of China. Their firewall was pretending to be the Tor servers and serving TCP Resets to block the traffic. This is really bad IMO. There are many totally legal reasons for using these tools - and we simply cannot have taxpayer dollars paying for a completely opaque firewall run by an un-accountable company in a public place. Not cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;future_of_web_apps&quot;&gt;Future of Web Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This presentation was by two Mozilla researchers, who showed what the latest browser technologies are, and what the future of the web tools will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
They demod the new HTML5 Canvas mode, and how easy and performant it was. They live-coded a simple text editor. Cool stuff. Felt very much like old school graphics programming, with bitblts and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;thunderbird&quot;&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
David Ascher gave an interesting talk on email and where Mozilla thunderbird is going. I have never considered using thunderbird, but their latest version may be cool enough to give it a try instead of Apple's Mail.app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
They have started providing useful summary views for folders, using the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://vis.stanford.edu/protovis/&quot;&gt;protovis&lt;/a&gt; library to produce very nice looking graphs showing your usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;identi_ca&quot;&gt;Identi.ca&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The final talk of Thursday was by Evan Prodromou about laconi.ca and identi.ca (microblogging). It kinda felt like a sales pitch as Evan talked all about what he has been doing to build a decentralized microblogging ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are two &amp;quot;emerging standards&amp;quot; if we can call them that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, laconi.ca uses the Twitter REST API, so that all the twitter clients &amp;quot;just work&amp;quot; with laconi.ca. We could consider doing this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Secondly, there is the openmicroblogging API to support federation to other servers and systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The interesting thing about laconi.ca's federation model is that it is not a server-to-server federation - it is a user-to-user federation. So I just subscribe to a user on another server (via a URL), and then those systems post messages back and forth. But there is no &amp;quot;server configuration&amp;quot;, it's all done on the user level with tools like oauth. I think this makes the problem space much simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;open_web_testing&quot;&gt;Open Web Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On Friday morning at 8:30 (gasp) I gave my talk on open web testing. My message was basically that you need a Balanced Breakfast of testing strategies - that automation is just one part of your strategy along with manual testing and unit testing. I showed how we at Socialtext had evolved our test strategy over time, from unit tests &amp;amp; manual testing (2006) to qa led wikitest automation (2007) to developer led wikitest automation (today).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can hear the first 5 minutes of my talk here: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://audioboo.fm/boos/29845&quot;&gt;http://audioboo.fm/boos/29845&lt;/a&gt; And you can find some notes from my preso here: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.openwebvancouver.ca/node/101&quot;&gt;http://www.openwebvancouver.ca/node/101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had really good feedback from this talk. I was a bit nervous going into it, as it wasn't a &amp;quot;tools talk&amp;quot;, where I made recommendations about which tools to use and how. Instead it was more about the team and the process and doing things with intention and looking at the broader picture. But the feedback was very positive exactly about this, @rtanglao even said, &amp;quot;This talk alone makes the conference worthwhile for me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'll be giving this same talk at YAPC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My slides are here: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://awesnob.com/web-testing/index.xul&quot;&gt;http://awesnob.com/web-testing/index.xul&lt;/a&gt;  (but it only works in Firefox)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;javascript_mobile_development_with_phonegap&quot;&gt;Javascript Mobile Development with PhoneGap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Some vancouver hackers I know at Nitobi gave a talk on a framework they've built called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://phonegap.com/&quot;&gt;PhoneGap&lt;/a&gt;, which allows developers to build HTML/CSS/JS applications that get bundled &amp;amp; built for mobile devices. They have created the &amp;quot;glue code&amp;quot; for iphone, bberry, and androids (with more coming) to provide simple Javascript APIs for all the cool features on these mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One of my hacker friends, Joe, had created a simple android app for the conference itself with the schedule and conference twitter screens. It was suuuuper useful. This weekend, I pulled down the source and started re-writing the app for the upcoming YAPC conference I'll be going to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;vancouver_s_open_data&quot;&gt;Vancouver's Open Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
@david_a_eaves gave a talk that presented what the City of Vancouver has just done to promote Open Data &amp;amp; Open Standards. The City became the first city in the world to pass an open data, open standards, open source motion. David explained that &amp;quot;all web 2.0 sites have a bargain to their users&amp;quot;. In this case, the bargain is that the city will begin to open up it's data, and in exchange us hackers need to build cool things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Really exciting stuff - the room was packed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After this talk and a quick lunch break, we had a &amp;quot;sandbox session&amp;quot; where several city staffers (the Head of the city's IT, and many others) sat with Open Web hackers in several small groups. We brainstormed where to go next with the open data, and then shared it at the end. Really awesome stuff. My favourite outcome was the creation of a vancouver-data google group to continue the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At the end of the session I gave a sincere thank you to the city folks for coming to &amp;quot;our turf&amp;quot; and taking time out of their day to talk with us as peers. I said it felt like &amp;quot;the future&amp;quot;. I was surprised as the room erupted with applause and a standing ovation for the city folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;open_web_open_mind&quot;&gt;Open Web, Open Mind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My friend @keeth gave a talk about meditation and some web resources. He is just launching a new site called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://findmeditation.com&quot;&gt;http://findmeditation.com&lt;/a&gt; that walks people through guided meditations and puts them in contact with a meditation instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Keith guided the audience through a 15m visualization exercise that seemed to fly by. Good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hackerspaces&quot;&gt;Hackerspaces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally I helped present a talk on HackerSpaces to an extremely small audience. It was super fun though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;wrap_up&quot;&gt;Wrap-up.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Overall it was incredibly energizing week-end and weekend. Lots of talk about social media and social tools within organizations, and lots of energy about citizen engagement. Excellent times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Great writeup Luke - Thanks for sharing your notes with us. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Re Thunderbird, I've been using 3.0b3pre nightly builds with the Leopard Mail-Default-Aqua extension -- it not only performs better than Mail.app, it even looks more Apple-ish than Mail.app. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/134155/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Audrey Tang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: audrey.tang@socialtext.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Jun 30 3:13pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=06-=30 22:13:00 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-06-30T22:13:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=17">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Console Collection</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2009/05/console-collection/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I added another item to my console collection!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/consoles2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;All of my consoles&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(Forgive the crappy mobile phone picture)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to acquire a Panasonic 3DO FZ-1 from a local dealer on the weekend. So far now, this is what I have in my console collection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nintendo Entertainment System (NES)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Super Famicom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nintendo Wii&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sega Genesis CDX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sega Saturn (Model 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sega Dreamcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony Playstation 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony Playstation 2 (Thin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panasonic 3DO FZ-1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still on the hunt for more of the obscure consoles.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-05-25T23:56:56+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?net_parliament">
	<title>lukec: Net-Parliament</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?net_parliament</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: Blog Post, government, open source, parliament, perl, Perl Necklace, Perl Programming&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've started hacking some code to scrape &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://parl.gc.ca&quot;&gt;http://parl.gc.ca&lt;/a&gt; and to pull down data on Members of Parliament, Government Bills and Voting details.  My idea is to pull down this data into a KiokuDB (cause I want to give it a whirl), and then to create a webapp that exposes this same data with a nice RESTful interface for other people to build on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So far, I've got the scraper code done as &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://github.com/lukec/cpan-net-parliament/tree/master&quot;&gt;Net::Parliament&lt;/a&gt;.  I'll probably push it up to CPAN once I feel it is ready and stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The other code I'm working on is called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://github.com/lukec/parlapi/tree/master&quot;&gt;parlapi&lt;/a&gt;, and it is a Catalyst webapp that will display the data scraped via Net::Parliament.  I hope to expose HTML, Text and JSON representations of most of the data, as well as splicing it up into different views.  Perhaps I'll throw in some &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://webhooks.org&quot;&gt;Webhooks&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'll try to keep this blog posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-05-21T08:12:26+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?my_open_source_calendar">
	<title>lukec: My open source calendar</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?my_open_source_calendar</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: blog post, git, github, open source, Perl Necklace&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I just (re-)discovered my Open Source Calendar that marks my contributions made on github to open projects.  So far my longest streak is 11 days. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wafl_block&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;seinfeld-badge user-lukec&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;me&quot; href=&quot;http://www.calendaraboutnothing.com/~lukec&quot;&gt;Calendar
	About Nothing&lt;/a&gt; tracks my public contributions on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- wiki:
.html
&lt;link rel==&quot;stylesheet&quot; href==&quot;http://www.calendaraboutnothing.com/styles/widget/reset.css&quot; media==&quot;screen, projection&quot; type==&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
&lt;link rel==&quot;stylesheet&quot; href==&quot;http://www.calendaraboutnothing.com/styles/widget/screen.css&quot; media==&quot;screen, projection&quot; type==&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
&lt;link rel==&quot;stylesheet&quot; href==&quot;http://www.calendaraboutnothing.com/styles/widget/seinfeld-=badge.css&quot; media==&quot;screen, projection&quot; type==&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class==&quot;seinfeld-=badge user-=lukec&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href==&quot;http://www.calendaraboutnothing.com/~lukec&quot; rel==&quot;me&quot;&gt;Calendar About Nothing&lt;/a&gt; tracks my public contributions on &lt;A href==&quot;http://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; &amp;lt;!-=-= .seinfeld-=badge .user-=lukec -=-=&gt;

    &amp;lt;!-=-= Using the new CDN for JS from Lindsay Evans -= http://jscdn.net/ -=-=&gt;
    &lt;script src==&quot;http://jscdn.net/jquery-=1.3.2.js&quot; type==&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &amp;lt;!-=-= // JSCDN hosting -=-=&gt;

    &amp;lt;!-=-= Adding Seinfeld CAN Badge -=-=&gt;
    &lt;script src==&quot;http://calendaraboutnothing.com/javascripts/widget/seinfeld-=badge.js&quot; type==&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &amp;lt;!-=-= // Seinfeld badge-=-=&gt;

    &amp;lt;!-=-= Calling JS fun -=-=&gt;
    &lt;script src==&quot;http://calendaraboutnothing.com/javascripts/widget/go.js&quot; type==&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &amp;lt;!-=-= // Calling JS fun -=-=&gt;
.html
--&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-05-11T07:20:24+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?thank_you_for_the_tests">
	<title>lukec: Thank you for the Tests</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?thank_you_for_the_tests</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: blog post, Perl Necklace&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If there is one thing the Perl hackers at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://socialtext.com&quot;&gt;Socialtext&lt;/a&gt; have to be thankful for, it is the generous number of unit tests left by the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://ingy.net&quot;&gt;founding&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://cdent.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;generation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://urbanape.com/&quot;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://search.cpan.org/~drolsky/&quot;&gt;developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We've now got ~16,000 unit tests, ~1,800 API tests, and ~20,000 selenium test steps covering Socialtext.  A solid run through this battery of tests gives us a lot of confidence in our software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When our team makeup shifted recently, we decided that the developers would convert the story tests into &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior-driven_development&quot;&gt;BDD&lt;/a&gt; style tests.  This then allows our talented qa people to spend more time with the product, testing and trying to break it.  Importantly, it allows our testers to &lt;em&gt;keep up with our developers&lt;/em&gt; without getting bogged down writing test automation.  Now that developers are writing behaviour level testing, we can start with high level failing tests, and then work our way through the story tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The power of this is liberating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So my appreciation goes out to all the past and present Socialtext hackers who keep us well tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-05-02T06:53:08+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?lightning_renegade">
	<title>lukec: Lightning Renegade</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?lightning_renegade</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: blog post, juggle, lightning talk, pattern, perl, Perl Necklace&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.vjf2009.com/&quot;&gt;2009 Victoria Juggling Festival&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to use my skills and present something at the Renegade Show.  Renegade is an MC'd open stage show where people are encouraged to try out crazy ideas and new tricks. It's generally hilarious and impressive.  This year was no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately this year, I've been doing way more facilitation and group work than I have been juggling.  I'm a pretty good juggler, but I feel there are others in the festival with much better presentations of those skills.  So I always try to do something fun and quirky, perhaps showcasing other people or working with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Several weeks ago, one of the festival organizers asked me to MC the Renegade show.  So I started collecting ideas.  Later on, we discovered that Tall Matt from Seattle had some good ideas for Renegade, so I was very happy to let him take the reigns.  He did a great job as the Renegade Police.  I talked with Matt early in the evening to suggest some ideas for the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I ended up doing 2 pieces in the show.  First up, About half way through, Officer Matt called up Inspector Closs to present the results of the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48172732@N00/3423435140/&quot;&gt;Jugglefest Poll&lt;/a&gt;  I had taken earlier in the evening.  The Poll was really fun to create, and then to get everyone to take it.  It was cool, cause I got to be present with almost everyone at the festival for a few minutes.  Presenting the results was pretty funny too.  The best heckle was when I commented, &amp;quot;Now this one I found interesting ...&amp;quot; and pointed at the question.  Tony Duncan shouted out, &amp;quot;FINALLY!&amp;quot;.  It was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For the second piece in the show, I decided to borrow an idea from the Perl Community, and the larger open source community.  I wanted to take the idea of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightning_Talk&quot;&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/a&gt; - a super fast rotation of several presentations to the juggling masses.  So before the show, I went around at asked 10 people if they could fill a 1 minute slot in my mini-show within a show.  Only 1 minute is a pretty low barrier, so many people that wouldn't normally be in the show jumped in.  I ended up with 13 acts, and being as it was the first one, I thought that was OK.  In the future, I'd keep it at 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So when I was called down, I asked all the performers to come down to the stage.  I set the ground rules: you have 1 minute (Matt had a timer), and you'll get the gong (in this case the tibetan chimes) if/when you go over.  And with that, I opened it up to the acts.  I had my ipod hooked up to the stereo, and played a different song (fairly randomly) for each performer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think this is a pretty good pattern - it encourages short little bits you wouldn't normally see, and helps build confidence for newer presenters/performers.  I would love to hear about other people copying this idea at other festivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-05-02T06:25:57+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://mikecantelon.com/138 at http://mikecantelon.com">
	<title>Mike Cantelon: Persistant stack class for PHP</title>
	<link>http://mikecantelon.com/story/persistant-stack-class-php</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I made a simple class that provides a simple SQLite-based persistant FIFO stack class for PHP 5 (similar conceptually to Stack::Persistent in Perl).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of times I've written Drupal scripts that run out of memory while trying to process large amounts of nodes (changing taxonomy, etc.). Adding them to a persistant stack, then doing them in batches, is an easy way to remedy this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example usage:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mikecantelon.com/story/persistant-stack-class-php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-04-29T21:40:00+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?2009_victoria_jugglefest_high_low_goal_crush_bane_surprise">
	<title>lukec: 2009 Victoria Jugglefest High Low Goal Crush Bane Surprise</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?2009_victoria_jugglefest_high_low_goal_crush_bane_surprise</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: Blog Post, festival, HLGCBS, juggle, juggling, Victoria&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hey folks, I thought I'd spam everyone with my &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.vjf2009.com/&quot;&gt;2009 Victoria Jugglefest&lt;/a&gt; Wrap-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, I have 2 pictures to share:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The official Poll results: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48172732@N00/3423435140/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48172732@N00/3423435140/in/photostream/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The official games results: &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48172732@N00/3422627499/&quot;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48172732@N00/3422627499/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I have some video footage, I'll probably put that up some where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here is my High/Low/Goal/Crush/Bane/Surprise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Highs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leaving vancouver on a beautiful friday afternoon with a van full of jugglers!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting to better know &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; new people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listening to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R7yfISlGLNU&quot;&gt;I'm on a Boat!&lt;/a&gt; as we boarded the BC Ferry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meeting the Vancouver hoop crew on the ferry &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really nice feedback on my poll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really positive feedback about my Lightning Renegade act&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A nice looking festival t-shirt!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Lows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ipod to stereo connector stopped working on the trip, but the silence was still enjoyable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no volley club&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the festival: YES - games &amp;amp; a poll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute something to renegade: YES - poll &amp;amp; lightning renegade: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the large pad: YES - was perfect for polls and games results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the best use of the jugglevan: YES - was almost always full&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Crushes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yuki's limbo-juggle skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Banes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;damn ipod connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Surprises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how many cool new people I got to know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how quickly the idea of a summer vancouver festival went from a joke in the ferry lineup to having possible locations, a chair and a vice chair!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What can I say, a near perfect festival!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-04-08T18:03:20+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?coming_up_in_2009">
	<title>lukec: Coming up in 2009</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?coming_up_in_2009</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: blog post&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My summer is starting to feel busy already!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Some highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jxqQHCrGbM4&quot;&gt;Victoria Juggling Festival&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I may have something to do with the Renegade Show (Friday night ~10pm at UVIC) - come if you're nearby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will probably run juggle games on Sunday - suuuper fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.openwebvancouver.ca/&quot;&gt;Open Web Vancouver Conference&lt;/a&gt; - June 11-12&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm thinking of proposing some talks for this conference. I really enjoyed several of the talks last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk ideas:&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something about building the open web behind the firewall. That's what we're doing at Socialtext, and I think it can be an interesting talk to see what technologies work and don't work outside of the public open web, in the private open web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can always give a talk about testing with open web technologies. The &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;inter-workspace link: open&quot; href=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/open/index.cgi?wiki_tests&quot;&gt;Wiki Tests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {link: open [Wiki Tests]} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; system we've built at Socialtext is really quite cutting edge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed Global Development for Fun and Profit - this is a talk I would like to give, similar to a talk on distributed agile I gave at the Agile Conference in 2007.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://webhooks.org&quot;&gt;Webhooks&lt;/a&gt; - I really dug giving a webhooks lightning talk at the last Vancouver Perl Mongers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And I really should dust off my &amp;quot;Juggling multiple languages in the enterprise environment&amp;quot; talk I gave at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.justanotherperlhacker.org/lightning/yapcna2005.shtml&quot;&gt;YAPC::NA 2005&lt;/a&gt; - it was really well received and fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;(external link)&quot; href=&quot;http://yapc10.org&quot;&gt;Yet Another Perl Conference 10!&lt;/a&gt; - A bunch of vancouver perl hackers will be going to Pittsburgh for YAPC!&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps I should give some of the above talk ideas there too. More bang for my presentation buck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beginning of July - Road trip in BC - Perhaps drive up to port hardy, take the ferry up to prince rupert, and then drive over to the rockies and then south and then east through the kooteneys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'd love feedback on any of the talk ideas (just hit the comment button), or on ideas for the trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Support your local economy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-03-25T06:55:30+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://mikecantelon.com/137 at http://mikecantelon.com">
	<title>Mike Cantelon: Theme a Drupal node using a suggested template</title>
	<link>http://mikecantelon.com/story/theme-drupal-node-using-suggested-template</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Drupal offers lots of template overriding possibilities via giving templates names that correspond to a node's path, ID, etc. but there's no &quot;official&quot; way to get Drupal to use a special-case template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mikecantelon.com/story/theme-drupal-node-using-suggested-template&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-03-20T20:43:02+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?2009_02_retreat_wrap_up">
	<title>lukec: 2009-02 Retreat Wrap up</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?2009_02_retreat_wrap_up</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: blog post, experiment, reflection, retreat&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm super happy to report back to the tribe that I just held (my first) day-long retreat here in Vancouver. After a retreat in Oaxaca, I really wanted to bring that energy and space to some of the people in my social network. It took me about 15 months of getting the right pieces in place and a friend putting his hand on my shoulder and saying, &amp;quot;Just pick a date, the rest will fall into place&amp;quot;. And so it did. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I put together a single day retreat, with 3 ~2h sessions, a lunch and snacks. Out of ~40 people invited, 20 came to the retreat. I booked the Dharma Lab in Vancouver, a open studio space used by yoga, martial arts and sitting groups. There were no chairs, instead we were offered the use of sitting pillows. :) Expecting to be sore the next day, I was surprised that all the feedback I got was positive (so far! :). Beth said, &amp;quot;Sitting on plastic chairs all day isn't comfortable either.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Largely based on Jerry's format of open dialog and light moderation, I drafted a rough agenda (which I kept mostly hidden from the group) with 3 broad questions for each session. Before the retreat, I had set up a Socialtext wiki for retreaters to create a little profile and contribute what their challenges and questions for 2009 were. The day before the retreat, I made notes of all the different questions, and fit them into the 3 sessions. I had all of this on an index card FTW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The idea I had in mind for the retreat at the start of 2009 was &amp;quot;making space&amp;quot;. How are we creating time and space in our lives for our various passions and pursuits? What are the parts of that we're having trouble with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before the retreat, Jen bought a set of bells that produced a beautiful tone. This was the first time I'd use bells with a group, and it was exciting! (ha!) I realized after the retreat that the bells really got people's ears going and externally focused, and it's almost like I tricked them into deep listening. :) During and after the retreat, several people mentioned that they normally have a very active internal dialogue going, but during the retreat they noticed it was absent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The bell led into silence, which hung in the group at times with what felt to me like excitement. I started each session with the main question, and then some of the patterns and related questions people had on the wiki. In each session, we started with a sweep around the circle - a brief introduction or an answer to a question. And then we went into discussion, and I would queue people when it got busy. At the end, I'd try to wrap it up and explain the next step. I really tried to not rush the silence away - to let everyone just &lt;em&gt;be there&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I guess my computer hacker background was front and centre when I didn't plan for any physical activities. Thankfully, River offered to lead the group through a fun &amp;quot;car and driver&amp;quot; exercise he learned while teaching at a Waldorf school. After we renamed it to &amp;quot;bicycle and driver&amp;quot; and played, we got into the third session refreshed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first session was a decompression session and opportunity for the group to find it's place. We started with the choices about time and the struggles with time that we were facing. The second session was about what each of us would do with unlimited resources. And the final session was about looking ahead specifically to 2009 and the questions the group was facing ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We started off with the idea that our lives often feel so hectic and busy as we try to get things done that it's hard to enjoy the now. The pressure we put on ourselves to do things, and the fear of missing out leads us to become stressed out. We talked about making choices about how we are spending our time, and to feel good about and accept those choices as the best choices we could have made at that time. On the other end of the spectrum is being happy with our chores, even finding joy in them. And then there is being happy to just be and not be busy with many projects. We talked about failure, and how some cultures (the software dudes) stressed learning from our failures and almost celebrating them. We talked about making public commitments to do things, or commitments to your social network to encourage you to follow through with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Looking forward, most retreaters felt they were on the right path and wanted to do more of the same - although now with renewed energy and focus. We talked about the desire to live in the city with friends and clubs and events and people. And the desire to also live out away from people in nature, and have all the fancy green eco-living alternative energizement. We talked about the good sides of co-ops and collaborative ownership, as well as some of the downsides. Many retreaters had visions to create places where their friends and family would feel comfortable to spend time. We talked about retreaters involved in group activities - brewing beer, pottery, hacking. We talked about children and families and how they change our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We finished up the retreat with most of the group at Radha, a local eatery for a big group meal with partners invited as well. It was a great way to celebrate and relax after a long, intense day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was worth doing, I don't often have good deep conversations with people in my social circle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to repeat this experiment in 9 to 15 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really like the hybrid model of living in the city, but spending time at a special place out of town a few days a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel more confident about my path and life plans. Perhaps this is better said that I'm accepting my path and enjoying it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found the term 'eco-slum' fascinating. It was used in a positive way to indicate thinking about ways to build basic human structures with design wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really liked the idea of putting a section on your resume called 'Failures' of projects or things you really messed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've already got ideas for the next retreat! :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
thats so great.&lt;br /&gt;
i hate that i missed this one- hopefully that wont happen next time!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/114990/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Melissa Knowles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: jermesin@gmail.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Mar 5 11:33am&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=03-=05 19:33:27 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Great retreat Luke! Look forward to the next one, if you'll have me again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;avatar&quot; src=&quot;http://www.socialtext.net/data/people/61287/small_photo&quot; /&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Chris Simmons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: simmons.chris@gmail.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Mar 6 3:38pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=03-=06 23:38:22 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-03-06T23:38:22+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?happy_new_year_2009">
	<title>lukec: Happy New Year 2009</title>
	<link>http://www.socialtext.net/lukec/index.cgi?happy_new_year_2009</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;Creator: Luke Closs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tags: blog post&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wafl_block&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/jebusthecat/3156059203/&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;460&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!-- wiki:
.html
&lt;a href==&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/jebusthecat/3156059203/&quot; border==&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src==&quot;http://awesnob.com/happynewyear2009.jpg&quot; width==&quot;460&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
.html
--&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(It was my wife's idea, I'm just a model.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(The drunk guy is Jen's brother.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Filming this was ridiculously fun - I recommend it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;rule-medium&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;contributed by &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;person unauthorized&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;realName&quot;&gt;Lloyd Budd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- wiki: {user: foolswisdom@gmail.com} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class=&quot;nlw_phrase&quot;&gt;Feb 2 2:15pm&lt;!-- wiki: {date: 2009-=02-=02 22:15:17 GMT} --&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2009-02-02T22:15:17+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=98">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Decoding a simple monoalphabetic substitution cipher</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2008/11/decoding-a-simple-monoalphabetic-substitution-cipher/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This form of encryption was used in ancient times as well as around the time of the Renaissance period of Medieval Europe. It's a pretty straight forward method of swapping letters in favour of others. It looks daunting to decode without knowing what the swapped bits are at first, but once you start to look at repetition and patterns, it becomes straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll use the following &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simonsingh.net/Stage_1.html&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;BT JPX RMLX PCUV AMLX ICVJP IBTWXVR CI M LMT'R PMTN, MTN YVCJX CDXV MWMBTRJ JPX AMTNGXRJBAH UQCT JPX QGMRJXV CI JPX YMGG CI JPX HBTW'R QMGMAX; MTN JPX HBTW RMY JPX QMVJ CI JPX PMTN JPMJ YVCJX. JPXT JPX HBTW'R ACUTJXTMTAX YMR APMTWXN, MTN PBR JPCUWPJR JVCUFGXN PBL, RC JPMJ JPX SCBTJR CI PBR GCBTR YXVX GCCRXN, MTN PBR HTXXR RLCJX CTX MWMBTRJ MTCJPXV. JPX HBTW AVBXN MGCUN JC FVBTW BT JPX MRJVCGCWXVR, JPX APMGNXMTR, MTN JPX RCCJPRMEXVR. MTN JPX HBTW RQMHX, MTN RMBN JC JPX YBRX LXT CI FMFEGCT, YPCRCXDXV RPMGG VXMN JPBR YVBJBTW, MTN RPCY LX JPX BTJXVQVXJMJBCT JPXVXCI, RPMGG FX AGCJPXN YBJP RAMVGXJ, MTN PMDX M APMBT CI WCGN MFCUJ PBR TXAH, MTN RPMGG FX JPX JPBVN VUGXV BT JPX HBTWNCL. JPXT AMLX BT MGG JPX HBTW'R YBRX LXT; FUJ JPXE ACUGN TCJ VXMN JPX YVBJBTW, TCV LMHX HTCYT JC JPX HBTW JPX BTJXVQVXJMJBCT JPXVXCI. JPXT YMR HBTW FXGRPMOOMV WVXMJGE JVCUFGXN, MTN PBR ACUTJXTMTAX YMR APMTWXN BT PBL, MTN PBR GCVNR YXVX MRJCTBRPXN. TCY JPX KUXXT, FE VXMRCT CI JPX YCVNR CI JPX HBTW MTN PBR GCVNR, AMLX BTJC JPX FMTKUXJ PCURX; MTN JPX KUXXT RQMHX MTN RMBN, C HBTW, GBDX ICVXDXV; GXJ TCJ JPE JPCUWPJR JVCUFGX JPXX, TCV GXJ JPE ACUTJXTMTAX FX APMTWXN; JPXVX BR M LMT BT JPE HBTWNCL, BT YPCL BR JPX RQBVBJ CI JPX PCGE WCNR; MTN BT JPX NMER CI JPE IMJPXV GBWPJ MTN UTNXVRJMTNBTW MTN YBRNCL, GBHX JPX YBRNCL CI JPX WCNR, YMR ICUTN BT PBL; YPCL JPX HBTW TXFUAPMNTXOOMV JPE IMJPXV, JPX HBTW, B RME, JPE IMJPXV, LMNX LMRJXV CI JPX LMWBABMTR, MRJVCGCWXVR, APMGNXMTR, MTN RCCJPRMEXVR; ICVMRLUAP MR MT XZAXGGXTJ RQBVBJ, MTN HTCYGXNWX, MTN UTNXVRJMTNBTW, BTJXVQVXJBTW CI NVXMLR, MTN RPCYBTW CI PMVN RXTJXTAXR, MTN NBRRCGDBTW CI NCUFJR, YXVX ICUTN BT JPX RMLX NMTBXG, YPCL JPX HBTW TMLXN FXGJXRPMOOMV; TCY GXJ NMTBXG FX AMGGXN, MTN PX YBGG RPCY JPX BTJXVQVXJMJBCT. JPX IBVRJ ACNXYCVN BR CJPXGGC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-98&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As you can see, &quot;JPX&quot; appears in the cipher text numerous times. One could deduce that it is likely the word &quot;the&quot;, as the letter 'E' is the most commonly-used letter in the English language, meaning that we have the following key in so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying this decoding produces this result (lowercase text being my own):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;BT the RMLe hCUV AMLe ICVth IBTWeVR CI M LMT'R hMTN, MTN YVCte CDeV MWMBTRt the AMTNGeRtBAH UQCT the QGMRteV CI the YMGG CI the HBTW'R QMGMAe; MTN the HBTW RMY the QMVt CI the hMTN thMt YVCte. theT the HBTW'R ACUTteTMTAe YMR AhMTWeN, MTN hBR thCUWhtR tVCUFGeN hBL, RC thMt the SCBTtR CI hBR GCBTR YeVe GCCReN, MTN hBR HTeeR RLCte CTe MWMBTRt MTCtheV. the HBTW AVBeN MGCUN tC FVBTW BT the MRtVCGCWeVR, the AhMGNeMTR, MTN the RCCthRMEeVR. MTN the HBTW RQMHe, MTN RMBN tC the YBRe LeT CI FMFEGCT, YhCRCeDeV RhMGG VeMN thBR YVBtBTW, MTN RhCY Le the BTteVQVetMtBCT theVeCI, RhMGG Fe AGCtheN YBth RAMVGet, MTN hMDe M AhMBT CI WCGN MFCUt hBR TeAH, MTN RhMGG Fe the thBVN VUGeV BT the HBTWNCL. theT AMLe BT MGG the HBTW'R YBRe LeT; FUt theE ACUGN TCt VeMN the YVBtBTW, TCV LMHe HTCYT tC the HBTW the BTteVQVetMtBCT theVeCI. theT YMR HBTW FeGRhMOOMV WVeMtGE tVCUFGeN, MTN hBR ACUTteTMTAe YMR AhMTWeN BT hBL, MTN hBR GCVNR YeVe MRtCTBRheN. TCY the KUeeT, FE VeMRCT CI the YCVNR CI the HBTW MTN hBR GCVNR, AMLe BTtC the FMTKUet hCURe; MTN the KUeeT RQMHe MTN RMBN, C HBTW, GBDe ICVeDeV; Get TCt thE thCUWhtR tVCUFGe thee, TCV Get thE ACUTteTMTAe Fe AhMTWeN; theVe BR M LMT BT thE HBTWNCL, BT YhCL BR the RQBVBt CI the hCGE WCNR; MTN BT the NMER CI thE IMtheV GBWht MTN UTNeVRtMTNBTW MTN YBRNCL, GBHe the YBRNCL CI the WCNR, YMR ICUTN BT hBL; YhCL the HBTW TeFUAhMNTeOOMV thE IMtheV, the HBTW, B RME, thE IMtheV, LMNe LMRteV CI the LMWBABMTR, MRtVCGCWeVR, AhMGNeMTR, MTN RCCthRMEeVR;&lt;br /&gt;
ICVMRLUAh MR MT eZAeGGeTt RQBVBt, MTN HTCYGeNWe, MTN UTNeVRtMTNBTW, BTteVQVetBTW CI NVeMLR, MTN RhCYBTW CI hMVN ReTteTAeR, MTN NBRRCGDBTW CI NCUFtR, YeVe ICUTN BT the RMLe NMTBeG, YhCL the HBTW TMLeN FeGteRhMOOMV; TCY Get NMTBeG Fe AMGGeN, MTN he YBGG RhCY the BTteVQVetMtBCT. the IBVRt ACNeYCVN BR CtheGGC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This appears to be successful. It is not an entirely reliable method as one could go without using the word, but using commonly used words as a start is always a good way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we begin to skim through some of the decoded text, we discover across still encoded but possible words such as &quot;theT&quot;, where the letter 'T' could really be the letter 'N' as there are not many likely words that would start with &quot;the&quot; but end with anything else. &quot;thMt&quot; could then imply that 'M' is really the letter 'A'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bn the RaLe hCUV AaLe ICVth IBnWeVR CI a Lan'R hanN, anN YVCte CDeV aWaBnRt&lt;br /&gt;
the AanNGeRtBAH UQCn the QGaRteV CI the YaGG CI the HBnW'R QaGaAe; anN the&lt;br /&gt;
HBnW RaY the QaVt CI the hanN that YVCte. then the HBnW'R ACUntenanAe YaR&lt;br /&gt;
AhanWeN, anN hBR thCUWhtR tVCUFGeN hBL, RC that the SCBntR CI hBR GCBnR&lt;br /&gt;
YeVe GCCReN, anN hBR HneeR RLCte Cne aWaBnRt anCtheV. the HBnW AVBeN aGCUN&lt;br /&gt;
tC FVBnW Bn the aRtVCGCWeVR, the AhaGNeanR, anN the RCCthRaEeVR. anN the&lt;br /&gt;
HBnW RQaHe, anN RaBN tC the YBRe Len CI FaFEGCn, YhCRCeDeV RhaGG VeaN thBR&lt;br /&gt;
YVBtBnW, anN RhCY Le the BnteVQVetatBCn theVeCI, RhaGG Fe AGCtheN YBth&lt;br /&gt;
RAaVGet, anN haDe a AhaBn CI WCGN aFCUt hBR neAH, anN RhaGG Fe the thBVN&lt;br /&gt;
VUGeV Bn the HBnWNCL. then AaLe Bn aGG the HBnW'R YBRe Len; FUt theE ACUGN&lt;br /&gt;
nCt VeaN the YVBtBnW, nCV LaHe HnCYn tC the HBnW the BnteVQVetatBCn&lt;br /&gt;
theVeCI. then YaR HBnW FeGRhaOOaV WVeatGE tVCUFGeN, anN hBR ACUntenanAe YaR&lt;br /&gt;
AhanWeN Bn hBL, anN hBR GCVNR YeVe aRtCnBRheN. nCY the KUeen, FE VeaRCn CI&lt;br /&gt;
the YCVNR CI the HBnW anN hBR GCVNR, AaLe BntC the FanKUet hCURe; anN the&lt;br /&gt;
KUeen RQaHe anN RaBN, C HBnW, GBDe ICVeDeV; Get nCt thE thCUWhtR tVCUFGe&lt;br /&gt;
thee, nCV Get thE ACUntenanAe Fe AhanWeN; theVe BR a Lan Bn thE HBnWNCL, Bn&lt;br /&gt;
YhCL BR the RQBVBt CI the hCGE WCNR; anN Bn the NaER CI thE IatheV GBWht&lt;br /&gt;
anN UnNeVRtanNBnW anN YBRNCL, GBHe the YBRNCL CI the WCNR, YaR ICUnN Bn&lt;br /&gt;
hBL; YhCL the HBnW neFUAhaNneOOaV thE IatheV, the HBnW, B RaE, thE IatheV,&lt;br /&gt;
LaNe LaRteV CI the LaWBABanR, aRtVCGCWeVR, AhaGNeanR, anN RCCthRaEeVR;&lt;br /&gt;
ICVaRLUAh aR an eZAeGGent RQBVBt, anN HnCYGeNWe, anN UnNeVRtanNBnW,&lt;br /&gt;
BnteVQVetBnW CI NVeaLR, anN RhCYBnW CI haVN RentenAeR, anN NBRRCGDBnW CI&lt;br /&gt;
NCUFtR, YeVe ICUnN Bn the RaLe NanBeG, YhCL the HBnW naLeN FeGteRhaOOaV;&lt;br /&gt;
nCY Get NanBeG Fe AaGGeN, anN he YBGG RhCY the BnteVQVetatBCn. the IBVRt&lt;br /&gt;
ACNeYCVN BR CtheGGC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we're starting to see more and more clearer words. The pattern &quot;anN&quot; is likely &quot;and&quot; (thus 'N' is 'D') due to its frequency within the paragraph--it could imply &quot;any&quot;, but grammatically it wouldn't make sense unless the encoding individual is trying to fool us. &quot;Bn&quot; also appears several times and it would make sense that it would stand for &quot;in&quot; due to its placement within the sentences, making 'B' equal to 'I'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the RaLe hCUV AaLe ICVth IinWeVR CI a Lan'R hand, and YVCte CDeV aWainRt&lt;br /&gt;
the AandGeRtiAH UQCn the QGaRteV CI the YaGG CI the HinW'R QaGaAe; and the&lt;br /&gt;
HinW RaY the QaVt CI the hand that YVCte. then the HinW'R ACUntenanAe YaR&lt;br /&gt;
AhanWed, and hiR thCUWhtR tVCUFGed hiL, RC that the SCintR CI hiR GCinR&lt;br /&gt;
YeVe GCCRed, and hiR HneeR RLCte Cne aWainRt anCtheV. the HinW AVied aGCUd&lt;br /&gt;
tC FVinW in the aRtVCGCWeVR, the AhaGdeanR, and the RCCthRaEeVR. and the&lt;br /&gt;
HinW RQaHe, and Raid tC the YiRe Len CI FaFEGCn, YhCRCeDeV RhaGG Vead thiR&lt;br /&gt;
YVitinW, and RhCY Le the inteVQVetatiCn theVeCI, RhaGG Fe AGCthed Yith&lt;br /&gt;
RAaVGet, and haDe a Ahain CI WCGd aFCUt hiR neAH, and RhaGG Fe the thiVd&lt;br /&gt;
VUGeV in the HinWdCL. then AaLe in aGG the HinW'R YiRe Len; FUt theE ACUGd&lt;br /&gt;
nCt Vead the YVitinW, nCV LaHe HnCYn tC the HinW the inteVQVetatiCn&lt;br /&gt;
theVeCI. then YaR HinW FeGRhaOOaV WVeatGE tVCUFGed, and hiR ACUntenanAe YaR&lt;br /&gt;
AhanWed in hiL, and hiR GCVdR YeVe aRtCniRhed. nCY the KUeen, FE VeaRCn CI&lt;br /&gt;
the YCVdR CI the HinW and hiR GCVdR, AaLe intC the FanKUet hCURe; and the&lt;br /&gt;
KUeen RQaHe and Raid, C HinW, GiDe ICVeDeV; Get nCt thE thCUWhtR tVCUFGe&lt;br /&gt;
thee, nCV Get thE ACUntenanAe Fe AhanWed; theVe iR a Lan in thE HinWdCL, in&lt;br /&gt;
YhCL iR the RQiVit CI the hCGE WCdR; and in the daER CI thE IatheV GiWht&lt;br /&gt;
and UndeVRtandinW and YiRdCL, GiHe the YiRdCL CI the WCdR, YaR ICUnd in&lt;br /&gt;
hiL; YhCL the HinW neFUAhadneOOaV thE IatheV, the HinW, i RaE, thE IatheV,&lt;br /&gt;
Lade LaRteV CI the LaWiAianR, aRtVCGCWeVR, AhaGdeanR, and RCCthRaEeVR;&lt;br /&gt;
ICVaRLUAh aR an eZAeGGent RQiVit, and HnCYGedWe, and UndeVRtandinW,&lt;br /&gt;
inteVQVetinW CI dVeaLR, and RhCYinW CI haVd RentenAeR, and diRRCGDinW CI&lt;br /&gt;
dCUFtR, YeVe ICUnd in the RaLe danieG, YhCL the HinW naLed FeGteRhaOOaV;&lt;br /&gt;
nCY Get danieG Fe AaGGed, and he YiGG RhCY the inteVQVetatiCn. the IiVRt&lt;br /&gt;
ACdeYCVd iR CtheGGC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, patterns start to become real clear. My guess is that &quot;aWainRt&quot; means &quot;against&quot;, implying that 'W' is 'G' and 'R' is 'S'. &quot;hiR&quot; would imply that 'R' is 'S' as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the saLe hCUV AaLe ICVth IingeVs CI a Lan's hand, and YVCte CDeV against&lt;br /&gt;
the AandGestiAH UQCn the QGasteV CI the YaGG CI the Hing's QaGaAe; and the&lt;br /&gt;
Hing saY the QaVt CI the hand that YVCte. then the Hing's ACUntenanAe Yas&lt;br /&gt;
Ahanged, and his thCUghts tVCUFGed hiL, sC that the SCints CI his GCins&lt;br /&gt;
YeVe GCCsed, and his Hnees sLCte Cne against anCtheV. the Hing AVied aGCUd&lt;br /&gt;
tC FVing in the astVCGCgeVs, the AhaGdeans, and the sCCthsaEeVs. and the&lt;br /&gt;
Hing sQaHe, and said tC the Yise Len CI FaFEGCn, YhCsCeDeV shaGG Vead this&lt;br /&gt;
YViting, and shCY Le the inteVQVetatiCn theVeCI, shaGG Fe AGCthed Yith&lt;br /&gt;
sAaVGet, and haDe a Ahain CI gCGd aFCUt his neAH, and shaGG Fe the thiVd&lt;br /&gt;
VUGeV in the HingdCL. then AaLe in aGG the Hing's Yise Len; FUt theE ACUGd&lt;br /&gt;
nCt Vead the YViting, nCV LaHe HnCYn tC the Hing the inteVQVetatiCn&lt;br /&gt;
theVeCI. then Yas Hing FeGshaOOaV gVeatGE tVCUFGed, and his ACUntenanAe Yas&lt;br /&gt;
Ahanged in hiL, and his GCVds YeVe astCnished. nCY the KUeen, FE VeasCn CI&lt;br /&gt;
the YCVds CI the Hing and his GCVds, AaLe intC the FanKUet hCUse; and the&lt;br /&gt;
KUeen sQaHe and said, C Hing, GiDe ICVeDeV; Get nCt thE thCUghts tVCUFGe&lt;br /&gt;
thee, nCV Get thE ACUntenanAe Fe Ahanged; theVe is a Lan in thE HingdCL, in&lt;br /&gt;
YhCL is the sQiVit CI the hCGE gCds; and in the daEs CI thE IatheV Gight&lt;br /&gt;
and UndeVstanding and YisdCL, GiHe the YisdCL CI the gCds, Yas ICUnd in&lt;br /&gt;
hiL; YhCL the Hing neFUAhadneOOaV thE IatheV, the Hing, i saE, thE IatheV,&lt;br /&gt;
Lade LasteV CI the LagiAians, astVCGCgeVs, AhaGdeans, and sCCthsaEeVs;&lt;br /&gt;
ICVasLUAh as an eZAeGGent sQiVit, and HnCYGedge, and UndeVstanding,&lt;br /&gt;
inteVQVeting CI dVeaLs, and shCYing CI haVd sentenAes, and dissCGDing CI&lt;br /&gt;
dCUFts, YeVe ICUnd in the saLe danieG, YhCL the Hing naLed FeGteshaOOaV;&lt;br /&gt;
nCY Get danieG Fe AaGGed, and he YiGG shCY the inteVQVetatiCn. the IiVst&lt;br /&gt;
ACdeYCVd is CtheGGC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now things become even more clearer. We start to see words like &quot;sentenAes&quot; which is obviously &quot;sentences&quot;, meaning that 'A' is 'C'. If this is the case, then this backs up that &quot;Lan&quot; means &quot;man&quot; as &quot;AaLe&quot; appears before it, and if 'A' is 'C', then 'L' is 'M'. We then see &quot;HingdCL&quot; and &quot;Hing&quot; appear, likely indicating &quot;king&quot; and &quot;kingdom&quot;. 'C' is then 'O', and then 'H' is 'K'. We've gotten a lot out of this now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're getting closer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the same hoUr came Iorth Iingers oI a man's hand, and wrote over against the candlestick Upon the plaster oI the wall oI the king's palace; and the king saw the part oI the hand that wrote. then the king's coUntenance was changed, and his thoUghts troUFled him, so that the Soints oI his loins were loosed, and his knees smote one against another. the king cried aloUd to Fring in the astrologers, the chaldeans, and the soothsaEers. and the king spake, and said to the wise men oI FaFElon, whosoever shall read this writing, and show me the interpretation thereoI, shall Fe clothed with scarlet, and have a chain oI gold aFoUt his neck, and shall Fe the third rUler in the kingdom. then came in all the king's wise men; FUt theE coUld not read the writing, nor make known to the king the interpretation thereoI. then was king FelshaOOar greatlE troUFled, and his coUntenance was changed in him, and his lords were astonished. now the KUeen, FE reason oI the words oI the king and his lords, came into the FanKUet hoUse; and the KUeen spake and said, o king, live Iorever; let not thE thoUghts troUFle thee, nor let thE coUntenance Fe changed; there is a man in thE kingdom, in whom is the spirit oI the holE gods; and in the daEs oI thE Iather light and Understanding and wisdom, like the wisdom oI the gods, was IoUnd in him; whom the king neFUchadneOOar thE Iather, the king, i saE, thE Iather, made master oI the magicians, astrologers, chaldeans, and soothsaEers; IorasmUch as an eZcellent spirit, and knowledge, and Understanding, interpreting oI dreams, and showing oI hard sentences, and dissolving oI doUFts, were IoUnd in the same daniel, whom the king named FelteshaOOar; now let daniel Fe called, and he will show the interpretation. the Iirst codeword is othello.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now see &quot;anotheV&quot; and &quot;oDeV&quot;, which implies &quot;another&quot; and if 'V' is 'R', then &quot;over&quot;, thus 'D' is 'V'. &quot;knoYGedge&quot; would imply &quot;knowledge&quot;, thus 'Y' is 'W' and 'G' is 'L'. &quot;inteVQVetation&quot; could imply &quot;interpretation&quot; with our acknowledgement of the letter 'V', so 'Q' is 'P'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the same hoUr same Iorth Iingers oI a man's hand, and wrote over against&lt;br /&gt;
the sandlestisk Uron the rlaster oI the wall oI the king's ralase; and the&lt;br /&gt;
king saw the rart oI the hand that wrote. then the king's soUntenanse was&lt;br /&gt;
shanged, and his thoUghts troUFled him, so that the Soints oI his loins&lt;br /&gt;
were loosed, and his knees smote one against another. the king sried aloUd&lt;br /&gt;
to Fring in the astrologers, the shaldeans, and the soothsaEers. and the&lt;br /&gt;
king srake, and said to the wise men oI FaFElon, whosoever shall read this&lt;br /&gt;
writing, and show me the interrretation thereoI, shall Fe slothed with&lt;br /&gt;
ssarlet, and have a shain oI gold aFoUt his nesk, and shall Fe the third&lt;br /&gt;
rUler in the kingdom. then same in all the king's wise men; FUt theE soUld&lt;br /&gt;
not read the writing, nor make known to the king the interrretation&lt;br /&gt;
thereoI. then was king FelshaOOar greatlE troUFled, and his soUntenanse was&lt;br /&gt;
shanged in him, and his lords were astonished. now the KUeen, FE reason oI&lt;br /&gt;
the words oI the king and his lords, same into the FanKUet hoUse; and the&lt;br /&gt;
KUeen srake and said, o king, live Iorever; let not thE thoUghts troUFle&lt;br /&gt;
thee, nor let thE soUntenanse Fe shanged; there is a man in thE kingdom, in&lt;br /&gt;
whom is the sririt oI the holE gods; and in the daEs oI thE Iather light&lt;br /&gt;
and Understanding and wisdom, like the wisdom oI the gods, was IoUnd in&lt;br /&gt;
him; whom the king neFUshadneOOar thE Iather, the king, i saE, thE Iather,&lt;br /&gt;
made master oI the magisians, astrologers, shaldeans, and soothsaEers;&lt;br /&gt;
IorasmUsh as an eZsellent sririt, and knowledge, and Understanding,&lt;br /&gt;
interrreting oI dreams, and showing oI hard sentenses, and dissolving oI&lt;br /&gt;
doUFts, were IoUnd in the same daniel, whom the king named FelteshaOOar;&lt;br /&gt;
now let daniel Fe salled, and he will show the interrretation. the Iirst&lt;br /&gt;
sodeword is othello.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;KUeen&quot; implies &quot;queen&quot; due to the nature of the text, so 'U' remains unchanged, but 'K' is 'Q'. &quot;troUFled&quot; likely means &quot;troubled&quot;, so 'F' is 'B'. These two discovers are backed up by &quot;FanKUet&quot; which should mean &quot;banquet&quot;. To make matters even easier, &quot;eZsellent&quot; stands out and it should mean &quot;excellent&quot;, which implies that we have 'X'. &quot;thE&quot; comes before &quot;Iather&quot;, which could come out as &quot;thy father&quot;, meaning we have found 'Y' and 'F'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you may run across spelling errors and so forth as you go along--some are quite evident in my decoding. This might mean that either you have made a mistake in your decoding (which can be fixable later), or the original document was either poorly-written or this was done on purpose to thwart any decryption attempts. Nonetheless, persevere and you should get your end result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;U&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Z&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;U&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we're almost there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the same hour came forth fingers of a man's hand, and wrote over against the candlestick upon the plaster of the wall of the king's palace; and the king saw the part of the hand that wrote. then the king's countenance was changed, and his thoughts troubled him, so that the Soints of his loins were loosed, and his knees smote one against another. the king cried aloud to bring in the astrologers, the chaldeans, and the soothsayers. and the king spake, and said to the wise men of babylon, whosoever shall read this writing, and show me the interpretation thereof, shall be clothed with scarlet, and have a chain of gold about his neck, and shall be the third ruler in the kingdom. then came in all the king's wise men; but they could not read the writing, nor make known to the king the interpretation thereof. then was king belshaOOar greatly troubled, and his countenance was changed in him, and his lords were astonished. now the queen, by reason of the words of the king and his lords, came into the banquet house; and the queen spake and said, o king, live forever; let not thy thoughts trouble thee, nor let thy countenance be changed; there is a man in thy kingdom, in whom is the spirit of the holy gods; and in the days of thy father light and understanding and wisdom, like the wisdom of the gods, was found in him; whom the king nebuchadneOOar thy father, the king, i say, thy father, made master of the magicians, astrologers, chaldeans, and soothsayers; forasmuch as an excellent spirit, and knowledge, and understanding, interpreting of dreams, and showing of hard sentences, and dissolving of doubts, were found in the same daniel, whom the king named belteshaOOar; now let daniel be called, and he will show the interpretation. the first codeword is othello.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we're left with &quot;nebuchadneOOar&quot; and &quot;belteshaOOar&quot;. Finding the meaning for 'O' is a matter of looking at the table that we have formed, and by doing that, we discover that the letter is either 'J' or 'Z'. We'll also notice that nowhere in the table are the letters 'S' or 'O' used, so we know that a letter is going to be missing from this document--either on purpose or by mistake. &quot;OOar&quot; is how the two words finish off, so when looking at the two repeating letters, it becomes clear that it is likely 'Z', so &quot;zzar&quot;. We now have this pieced together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shifted bits:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;U&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Z&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Actual:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Z&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;S&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;U&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have it all in one piece!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;in the same hour came forth fingers of a man's hand, and wrote over against the candlestick upon the plaster of the wall of the king's palace; and the king saw the part of the hand that wrote. then the king's countenance was changed, and his thoughts troubled him, so that the joints of his loins were loosed, and his knees smote one against another. the king cried aloud to bring in the astrologers, the chaldeans, and the soothsayers. and the king spake, and said to the wise men of babylon, whosoever shall read this writing, and show me the interpretation thereof, shall be clothed with scarlet, and have a chain of gold about his neck, and shall be the third ruler in the kingdom. then came in all the king's wise men; but they could not read the writing, nor make known to the king the interpretation thereof. then was king belshazzar greatly troubled, and his countenance was changed in him, and his lords were astonished. now the queen, by reason of the words of the king and his lords, came into the banquet house; and the queen spake and said, o king, live forever; let not thy thoughts trouble thee, nor let thy countenance be changed; there is a man in thy kingdom, in whom is the spirit of the holy gods; and in the days of thy father light and understanding and wisdom, like the wisdom of the gods, was found in him; whom the king nebuchadnezzar thy father, the king, i say, thy father, made master of the magicians, astrologers, chaldeans, and soothsayers; forasmuch as an excellent spirit, and knowledge, and understanding, interpreting of dreams, and showing of hard sentences, and dissolving of doubts, were found in the same daniel, whom the king named belteshazzar; now let daniel be called, and he will show the interpretation. the first codeword is othello.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty straight forward!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2008-11-17T04:53:26+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=88">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Which candidate hosts in Canada?</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2008/10/which-candidate-hosts-in-canada/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/canadamap.gif&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;The Conservative Party of Canada prides itself on buying Canadian goods. It presents it as a party for all Canadians (of the right-leaning variety, of course) and puts an emphasis on &quot;Canada-first&quot; qualities (with some American influence, of course). Going into the 2008 elections, I have begun to wonder how &quot;Canadian&quot; some of these candidates are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a technically-minded guy, I decided to see which candidates in Metro Vancouver are using Canadian hosting providers for their campaign websites. The results are a bit staggering and somewhat disappointing. Even this terrible website is being hosted on a server in Canada, so why can't some of these candidates?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-88&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;List of Candidates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conservative Party of Canada&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Riding&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Candidate&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Website&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Country&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abbotsford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ed West&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://edfast.ca&quot;&gt;edfast.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Burnaby-Douglas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ronald Leung&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ronaldleung.ca&quot;&gt;ronaldleung.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Burnaby-New Westminster&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sam Rahkra&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://samrahkra.ca&quot;&gt;samrahkra.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Delta-Richmond East&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;John Cummins&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reelectjohncummins.com&quot;&gt;reelectjohncummins.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fleetwood-Port Kells&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nina Grewal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ninagrewal.ca&quot;&gt;ninagrewal.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Langley&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mark Warawa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New Westminster-Coquitlam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yonah Martin&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://yonahmartin.ca&quot;&gt;yonahmartin.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Newton-North Delta&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sandeep Pandher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sandeeppandher.ca&quot;&gt;sandeeppandher.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;North Vancouver&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andrew Saxton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewsaxton.ca&quot;&gt;andrewsaxton.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pitt Meadows-Maple Ridge-Mission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Randy Kamp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://randykamp.com&quot;&gt;randykamp.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Port Moody-Westwood-Port Coquitlam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;James Moore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesmoore.org&quot;&gt;jamesmoore.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Richmond&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alice Wong&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alicewong.ca&quot;&gt;alicewong.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South Surrey-White Rock-Cloverdale&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Russ Hiebert&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://russhiebert.ca&quot;&gt;russhiebert.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Surrey North&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dona Cadman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/feed/donacadman.ca&quot;&gt;donacadman.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver Centre&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lorne Mayencourt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver East&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ryan Warawa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver Kingsway&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Solomon Rayek&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver Quadra&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deborah Meredith&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://deborahmeredith.ca&quot;&gt;deborahmeredith.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver South&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wai Young &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://waiyoung.ca&quot;&gt;waiyoung.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;West Vancouver-Sunshine Coast-Sea to Sky Country&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;John Weston&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://johnweston.ca&quot;&gt;johnweston.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Liberal Party of Canada&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Riding&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Candidate&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Website&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Country&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abbotsford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lionel Traverse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Burnaby-Douglas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bill Cunningham&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://billcunningham.ca&quot;&gt;billcunningham.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Burnaby-New Westminster&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gerry Lenoski&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Delta-Richmond East&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dana Miller&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://danamiller.ca&quot;&gt;danamiller.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fleetwood-Port Kells&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brenda Locke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brendalocke.ca&quot;&gt;brendalocke.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Langley&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jake Gray&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New Westminster-Coquitlam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Michelle Hassen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Newton-North Delta&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sukh Dhaliwal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://votesukh.ca&quot;&gt;votesukh.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;North Vancouver&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Don Bell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://donbell.ca&quot;&gt;donbell.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pitt Meadows-Maple Ridge-Mission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dan Olson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Port Moody-Westwood-Port Coquitlam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ron McKinnon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ron-mckinnon.liberal.ca&quot;&gt;ron-mckinnon.liberal.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Richmond&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Raymond Chan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://raymondchan.ca&quot;&gt;raymondchan.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South Surrey-White Rock-Cloverdale&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Judy Higginbotham&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://judyhigginbotham.liberal.ca&quot;&gt;judyhigginbotham.liberal.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Surrey North&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Marc Muhammad&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver Centre&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hedy Fry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hedyfry.com&quot;&gt;hedyfry.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver East&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ken Low&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kenlow.liberal.ca&quot;&gt;kenlow.liberal.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver Kingsway&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wendy Yuan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wendyyuan.ca&quot;&gt;wendyyuan.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver Quadra&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joyce&lt;br /&gt;
  Murray&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver South&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ujjal&lt;br /&gt;
  Dosanjh&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;West Vancouver-Sunshine Coast-Sea to Sky&lt;br /&gt;
  Country&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ian&lt;br /&gt;
    Sutherland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://iansutherland.liberal.ca&quot;&gt;iansutherland.liberal.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ed: Lists for the NDP and the Greens have gone missing. I will make an attempt to find them in the future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How I determine this&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are a number of tools on the Internet that the average user could use to determine this sort of thing, I just used the tools provided with Mac OS X. Two simple commands provided me with the information to make this determination as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[ckeigher@sedna:~] $ host russhiebert.ca
russhiebert.ca has address 69.89.27.247
russhiebert.ca mail is handled by 10 mail.russhiebert.ca.
russhiebert.ca mail is handled by 21 mail2.russhiebert.ca.
[ckeigher@sedna:~] $ whois 69.89.27.247

OrgName:    Bluehost Inc.
OrgID:      BLUEH-2
Address:    1215 N. Research Way Q-3500
City:       Orem
StateProv:  UT
PostalCode: 84097
Country:    US

NetRange:   69.89.16.0 - 69.89.31.255
CIDR:       69.89.16.0/20
OriginAS:   AS11798
NetName:    BLUEHOST-NETWORK-1
NetHandle:  NET-69-89-16-0-1
Parent:     NET-69-0-0-0-0
NetType:    Direct Allocation
NameServer: NS1.BLUEHOST.COM
NameServer: NS2.BLUEHOST.COM
Comment:
RegDate:    2006-10-02
Updated:    2007-11-02

RAbuseHandle: NOC2320-ARIN
RAbuseName:   Network Operations Center
RAbusePhone:  +1-801-765-9400
RAbuseEmail:  abuse@bluehost.com

RNOCHandle: TECHN497-ARIN
RNOCName:   Technical Operations
RNOCPhone:  +1-801-765-9400
RNOCEmail:  support@bluehost.com

RTechHandle: NETWO2081-ARIN
RTechName:   Network Operations
RTechPhone:  +1-801-765-9400
RTechEmail:  netops@bluehost.com

OrgTechHandle: SAL72-ARIN
OrgTechName:   Alligood, Steve
OrgTechPhone:  +1-801-765-9400
OrgTechEmail:  steve@bluehost.com

# ARIN WHOIS database, last updated 2008-09-12 19:10
# Enter ? for additional hints on searching ARIN's WHOIS database.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the data given from the WHOIS programme, I was able to determine that the owner of the IP address given by the HOST command was based in the state of Utah in the United States. Some results don't give addresses but instead the name of the IP owner. In these cases it may just give off a telephone company (such as Bell or TELUS) or some obscure hosting company (in which case you just perform a search on Google for).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why should candidates host in Canada?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple: buy Canadian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially in Metro Vancouver's case, there is a plethora of well-priced hosting solutions that are hosted in Canada. This website is hosted by an organization that specializes in hosting non-profit websites (which would fit for all candidates), but even the unrestrictive hosting providers provide hosting solutions at a respectable price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If these candidates are looking elsewhere for their solutions, then it is only fair to say that Canadian interests do not come first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because it has a Canadian top-level domain (TLD) (&quot;.ca&quot;), it doesn't mean that it is hosted in Canada. My old blog has a .ca TLD and had its servers in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see one of these candidates or any other candidate, ask them where their website is hosted (physically).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2008-10-03T04:38:06+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=3">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Text messaging malarky</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2008/07/text-messaging-malarky/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://telusmobility.ca&quot;&gt;TELUS Mobility&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bell.ca&quot;&gt;Bell Mobility&lt;/a&gt; are screwing Canadians and are also lying about it in the process. In an announcement made earlier this week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.canada.com/theprovince/news/story.html?id=8c114a53-2000-4831-a04c-eee3fcb535ba&quot;&gt;both carriers plan to charge users $0.15 per received message&lt;/a&gt; instead of not charging at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is of course totally unfair to those who do not have any text messaging packages on their service plans already, and it basically punishes anyone who receives a text message whether or not they want to receive any to begin with.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-3&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a good laugh when I read this in the attached article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shawn Hall of Telus in Vancouver said the cost of accommodating text messaging has ballooned in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Canadians send 45 million text messages a day,&quot; said Hall. &quot;That has created a tremendous strain on our network and we can no longer afford to provide the service for free.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has a clue about networking knows that this is complete bullshit. If you're familiar with computer measurement terms, here's a demonstration of why text messaging is a drop in a bucket compared to voice calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average text message is probably around 70 characters, but if you include headers, it probably works out to 120 (the max characters for any message is 160). This means that about 120 bytes is transferred from handset to handset when a text message is made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Messages/day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avg. msg. bytes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total msg. data/day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.03 GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, 5 GB is quite a lot. In fact, the largest iPod Nano is at 8 GB, so that is indeed a lot of text data. However, it is nowhere near as much data as a voice call. A typical voice call is about 3 minutes, and depending on the carrier, each call runs about 9.6 to 12 kilobits per second (an MP3 typically has about 160 or so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's assume that about 19,000,000 calls are made in Canada on a mobile phone. We'll use an average of 11 Kbps for the call quality as that is a decent ballpark average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avg. call (seconds):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitrate (Kbps):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calls/day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GB/day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4,484.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TB/day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.38&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, text messaging is less than 0.5% of the total data than that the average daily calls generate. Most cell phone companies charge about $0.07 per minute for going over your allotment of minutes per month and yet somehow TELUS and Bell are claiming that the lack of charges are costing them a fortune in bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the two companies being greedy and nothing but. These numbers prove that they're a bunch of bullshitters.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2008-07-09T19:19:33+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=8">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: I want a refund for my music</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2008/06/i-want-a-refund-for-my-music/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have a question for all IP holders who are demanding that we have our copyright law changed to reflect their wishes: will you refund me my money when the technology that contains their material becomes almost unusable?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A case in point: my parentsâ€™ cassette tapes. In their library, they have something along the lines of about 70-90 cassette tapes that realistically cannot be played anymore. If you walk into almost any electronics store, nobody in their right mind will be selling tape decks. You can certainly buy them used, but at that point, youâ€™re running the risk of having a malfunction due to the nature of how a tape deck works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why I bring up cassettes is that I want to contrast it to what the music industry is adopting: that is the whole issue of digital rights management (DRM). In todayâ€™s digital music field, there are two common DRM products: Appleâ€™s Fairplay and Microsoftâ€™s PlaysForSure. Both of these products ensure that whoever has purchased the music is the only individual that can play it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I see with this is quite simple: what happens if Microsoft or Apple change the format or go out of business? These audio files are authenticated against services provided by the two companies, and if they go out of business, does this mean that my music collection no longer will play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I am well ahead of that problem for one simple reason: all of my music is DRM-free because I have copied my music from compact discs that I have bought. Thanks to todayâ€™s copyright law, I am entitled to the right of copying material that I already own and even in the event that the label behind the discâ€™s release goes extinct, it will still mean that I can still play their music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new copyright law as proposed in Bill C-61 will make me a criminal for circumventing this tactic. In an essence, I will have to repurchase an album from the new IP holder if the former goes bankrupt. I will not be allowed to rip any CDs I buy and play them on my computer or iPod where the disc will not be in place. I will effectively be â€œlocked inâ€ into using whatever medium theyâ€™ve chosen and have no freedom in how I choose to listen to their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When CDs are no longer available, will I be able to ask these IP holders whether or not I can get a refund?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digital-copyright.ca/&quot;&gt;Digital Copyright Canada&lt;/a&gt; provides a good resource on what is happening with copyright in our country. Don't let us become the 51st state.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2008-06-26T21:26:42+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=46">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: A view from up-top</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2008/02/a-view-from-up-top/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/dao_snapshot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently made a trip to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hia-iha.nrc-cnrc.gc.ca/dao/index_e.html&quot;&gt;Dominion Astrophysical Observatory&lt;/a&gt; just outside of Victoria. It was an impressive tour as I hadnâ€™t seen a real observatory before (this is the lone spectro-optical observatory on Canadian soil). The two 1.8 and 1.2 metre telescopes were damn impressive, but I couldnâ€™t really say that they were much better than this view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance, do check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hia-iha.nrc-cnrc.gc.ca/cu/main_e.html&quot;&gt;Centre of the Universe&lt;/a&gt; public outreach centre that they have onsite. They offer tours of the two telescopes and you get the added treat of being able to see the capital city of British Columbia from an elevation of 400 metres.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2008-02-11T23:46:57+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=52">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: â€˜BEEPâ€™ goes the check-outâ€“â€oh shiâ€¦â€ goes the cashier</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2008/01/%e2%80%98beep%e2%80%99-goes-the-check-out%e2%80%93%e2%80%9doh-shi%e2%80%a6%e2%80%9d-goes-the-cashier/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/barcode.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is in this seemingly innocent barcode? Well, if youâ€™re a fan of xkcd, you might be able to &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/327/&quot;&gt;guess&lt;/a&gt;. For the barcode-inept, the code reads the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Robert'); DROP TABLE Students;--&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comes in light of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.heise-security.co.uk/news/101151&quot;&gt;recent presentation&lt;/a&gt; taken place at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://events.ccc.de/congress/2007/Main_Page&quot;&gt;24th Chaos Computer Congress (24C3)&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin, Germany. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phenoelit.de/202/index.html&quot;&gt;Phenoelit&lt;/a&gt; gave the presentation and I would have to say that it opened up my eyes to the common insecurity of barcodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was proposing an event ticket system, I was considering a system using the aforementioned in the articles and video, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/barcode/&quot;&gt;GNU Barcode&lt;/a&gt;. Never once did I give any thought to possible SQL injections, buffer overflows, or anything else of that ilk when I considered sending confirmation PDFs via e-mail containing a scannable document that could be used instead of providing proper identification. I can tell you that if I do end up working with such things in the future that I will be careful to harden anything including barcode reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In light of this, I immediately began to scour anything in my wallet containing some sort of barcode. For the longest time, I have been more or less interested in solely on what is on the magstripe on them, but now the barcodes are of curiosity to me. I did discover something with my Safeway card (and the pile that I took before I left the company), but I will be toying with them and will later report on what I find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting on where it goes from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ed: It has been well over a year and a half since I wrote this. I probably should do something about what I said I would do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2008-01-02T02:53:16+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=54">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Goodbye old friendâ€¦</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2007/12/goodbye-old-friend%e2%80%a6/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/netscape_logo.png&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2007/12/29/aol_kills_netscape/&quot;&gt;AOL has killed Netscapeâ€¦&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a long time coming considering that the browser originated out of those involved with the original NCSA Mosaic project in the 90s. When Netscape Navigator was launched in 1994, it was seen as the superior browser to the original graphical Mosaic, and this eventually lead to its demise in 1997. In fact, Mosaic was completely gone from most peopleâ€™s computers when Microsoft determined that there was no Mosaic code left in their Internet Explorer software (this was when 7.0 was released).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I used Netscape up until version 4. When Microsoft came out with version 4.0 of their browser, it was decided by many (including myself) that it was time to jump ship and use the browser that was integrated with Windows. Netscapeâ€™s usage declined rapidly and even though there was a â€œbrowser warâ€ in the late 90s, it was quite clear who the overall winner was going to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually it got bought by AOL and eventually forked off to become two different entities. The Mozilla Project eventually became the open-source code base for Netscapeâ€™s later versions and because of this, itâ€™s not entirely dead. Firefox and Thunderbird have both proven to be proven competitors to Microsoftâ€™s offerings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that the strangest overall feature of more recent versions of Netscape was the fact that you could switch rendering engines on the Windows version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To leave you all off, hereâ€™s how Netscape Navigator 4 (which is in my opinion the last best version) would function todayâ€¦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/netscape/01.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying a browser or associated software is a bit strange to me these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/netscape/02.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default home page it would go to doesnâ€™t exist any longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/netscape/03.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of CSS support, PNG rendering, and modern HTML tags makes my blog lack any sort of design.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2007-12-30T23:57:59+00:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://keyboardcowboy.ca/?p=58">
	<title>Keyboard Cowboy: Untraceable: Another hacker thriller gone wrong!</title>
	<link>http://keyboardcowboy.ca/2007/12/untraceable-another-hacker-thriller-gone-wrong/</link>
	<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;With a new year comes a new crop of terrible movies. One movie in particular is &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Untraceable&quot;&gt;Untraceable&lt;/a&gt;, a psycho-hacker-killer thriller where someone has managed to rig up a web server to slowly kill someone by having some liquid injected into his prey every time someone visits an untraceable website. You can view the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/trailers/sony_pictures/untraceable/&quot;&gt;awful trailer&lt;/a&gt; and see for yourself how terrible it looks and will likely be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the idea of rigging up a web server to do such a task is entirely plausible, I laugh at the fact that the IP address is entirely untraceable to the point where they have no idea where the web server is or anything. From the looks of it, the killer is placing some sort of camera hooked to a broadband line. If my assumption is right, even with the fastest connection, if that is the main feed for the video and the traffic as a whole, Iâ€™d be curious to what the hell the killer is spending in bandwidth per month. I think that working for an ISP for so long has made me think this way, sadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to snag some screenshots from the dumb trailer and already I can see that this movie is destined to be the 2008 movie yearâ€™s first train wreck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/01.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just another day in the high-tech world of counter-cyber crime! Looks like sheâ€™s using Windows Vista!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/02.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey! I found this website! Itâ€™s a real killer! Too soon? Shit. Well, we better look!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/03.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the hell? This looks like a bloody anti-smoking website! Why is his jaw all fucked up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/04.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shit! This guy is being killed! Oh! I hope that you donâ€™t mind, but I placed an out-of-order system log from your Mac on to my computer. It might seem useless, but maybe it will help us figure out why these reserved IPs are blackholed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/05.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yo! We found this killer website! Donâ€™t go to it, but hereâ€™s the web address! If you go to this web address, youâ€™ll end up being an accessory to murder. Donâ€™t go to this web address that I have given everyone here in their notes and have pasted on this whiteboard to the left of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/06.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait a secondâ€¦? Why is the hostname resolving to that IP address, but the ICMP replies are from somewhere else? Holy shit! This is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ws.arin.net/whois/?queryinput=192.010.129.120&quot;&gt;oldest ARIN registrants&lt;/a&gt; out there! Maybe we should look into the address that ARIN is giving us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/07.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using my kick-ass dual-monitor set up not only to assist in a murder but to also check out some useless file relating to my fonts! Donâ€™t mind the lotion next to the left monitor, guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/08.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the IPs are changing around again. Maybe itâ€™s some sort of bizarre load-balancer? He could have multiple pipes? One of the IPs belongs to a guy in California. The guy who owns it works for Cisco, which must mean that he is an elite computer hacker!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/09.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The killer has enough time to put some sort of remote controlled camera on some very expensive BMW car. Not only does he stuff a body in the trunk, break FCC interference policies by somehow getting the video feed to show up on their LCD monitor, but he blows a few ten thousand on a fancy car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://keyboardcowboy.ca/images/blog/untraceable/10.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but he can hack into your car and remotely turn it off! Shit. I will never buy a Ford vehicle with Microsoftâ€™s Sync product. I donâ€™t need some douchebag remotely turning my car off like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hereâ€™s the deal, guys. Give me the IPs, some information about your network and where stuff is located, and I will spend the entire day going through your building, following cables to wherever the server is located. Servers have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techweb.com/wire/story/TWB20010409S0012&quot;&gt;gone missing before&lt;/a&gt;, and I am sure that with enough time, I could solve your mystery so you can get this â€˜wilyâ€™ hacker off of your backs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
	<dc:date>2007-12-26T20:09:11+00:00</dc:date>
</item>

</rdf:RDF>
